<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cladding on The Miette</title>
    <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/cladding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cladding on The Miette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 11:08:26 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/cladding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jan Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-jan-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-jan-build-update/</guid>
      <description>Our first update for 2024! 2024 has well and truly started with what feels like a huge January. Among the noteworthy developments was new eye protection! But jokes aside, we got some new eye-glasses from Bunnings and these are crystal clear with exceptional comfort, with Erny forgetting that they’re even on his face or on his head. They have swiftly become an indispensable asset — and it’s the little things, you know?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Update For 2023</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-final-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-final-build-update/</guid>
      <description>Our Last 2023 Build Update Hello and happy new year! We hope your break was filled with relaxation and joy. Ours was a mix of hard work and a few breakthroughs in our tiny house project. Let&amp;rsquo;s catch you up on our latest adventures.
Table Of ContentsChristmas Chronicles Welcoming the New Year with Wall #3 January Goals What&amp;rsquo;s next? Christmas Chronicles Did anyone experience hail in your area? We were, once again, in a relentless race against daylight and unpredictable weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-nov-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-nov-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A November build update Greetings from our ever-evolving construction site! November has been a month of highs, lows, and, of course, more cladding adventures. So, grab your virtual hard hat, and let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the nitty-gritty details.
Table Of ContentsMaking Our Soffits Pretty (and giving us headaches) What’s next? Our journey begins with drumroll… putting finishing touches on a wall, and oh, what a journey it has been. The internal debate raged on: to cover the corner where cladding meets, should we go with Surfmist steel corner flashing or the charm of contrasting wood trim?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September October Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A September holiday and an October build update 👋 Well hello there! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since our last blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy exploring the big wild world. Back on home soil we crack on with cladding the house 🏠
Table Of ContentsWhat we returned to in October What’s next? The past months have been a whirlwind of adventure, starting with a journey to the United States for a wedding - congratulations Visrut and Ruhani!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jul-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jul-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A July build update Windows are in!
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Working on the water pooling solution What’s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done July has been window month. We are pretty proud to say that we&amp;rsquo;ve now got our hand made windows installed 🙂 - here is how it went!
We began with the bathroom window, which we thought would be a breeze. However, not even one window down we faced our first hiccup - it turns out the width of the window frame was not wide enough to run flush with the internal lining of the tiny house (on the inside) and flush with the exterior cladding on the outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jun-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jun-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A June build update A lot of shopping and finally finishing sanding the cladding!
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done The tail end of May and the month of June have been quite eventful, filled with a lot of shopping and unexpected visitors from far away states. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in!
Our fanciest acquisition was a package of flathead brass screws that arrived in the mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August September 2022 Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 13:54:47 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</guid>
      <description>An August September build update Hello Spring! Working almost every weekend, these last two months we&amp;rsquo;ve actually got a proper build update 😄.
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done We went through our stash of 90x45mm lengths and picked out roof rafters. These have been measured down to a 20 degree angle and some have been cut to size! We&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this in the garage when there has been a rain shower break and it has worked quite well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
