<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tiny_house on The Miette</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/tiny_house/</link><description>Recent content in Tiny_house on The Miette</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 11:08:26 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/tiny_house/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jan Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-jan-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-jan-build-update/</guid><description>Our first update for 2024! 2024 has well and truly started with what feels like a huge January. Among the noteworthy developments was new eye protection! But jokes aside, we got some new eye-glasses from Bunnings and these are crystal clear with exceptional comfort, with Erny forgetting that they’re even on his face or on his head. They have swiftly become an indispensable asset — and it’s the little things, you know?</description></item><item><title>Final Update For 2023</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-final-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-final-build-update/</guid><description>Our Last 2023 Build Update Hello and happy new year! We hope your break was filled with relaxation and joy. Ours was a mix of hard work and a few breakthroughs in our tiny house project. Let&amp;rsquo;s catch you up on our latest adventures.
Table Of Contents Christmas Chronicles Welcoming the New Year with Wall #3 January Goals What&amp;rsquo;s next? Christmas Chronicles Did anyone experience hail in your area? We were, once again, in a relentless race against daylight and unpredictable weather.</description></item><item><title>November Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-nov-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-nov-build-update/</guid><description>A November build update Greetings from our ever-evolving construction site! November has been a month of highs, lows, and, of course, more cladding adventures. So, grab your virtual hard hat, and let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the nitty-gritty details.
Table Of Contents Making Our Soffits Pretty (and giving us headaches) What’s next? Our journey begins with drumroll… putting finishing touches on a wall, and oh, what a journey it has been. The internal debate raged on: to cover the corner where cladding meets, should we go with Surfmist steel corner flashing or the charm of contrasting wood trim?</description></item><item><title>September October Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</guid><description>A September holiday and an October build update 👋 Well hello there! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since our last blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy exploring the big wild world. Back on home soil we crack on with cladding the house 🏠
Table Of Contents What we returned to in October What’s next? The past months have been a whirlwind of adventure, starting with a journey to the United States for a wedding - congratulations Visrut and Ruhani!</description></item><item><title>August Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-aug-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-aug-build-update/</guid><description>An August build update Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done An aside about our skylight flashing The concept of a 1.5 person job We&amp;rsquo;re back with another exciting update from our construction escapades. August has been a whirlwind of challenges, cleaning, and mad dash purchases but we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to make some significant roofing progress on our tiny house. Buckle up, because we&amp;rsquo;ve got quite the adventure to share!
What we&amp;rsquo;ve done As we kicked off August, we found ourselves juggling two passions: our relentless dedication to our tiny house project (read as: desperation to finish the roof before we leave for the US) and the thrilling tension of the Women&amp;rsquo;s World Cup (go the Matildas!</description></item><item><title>July Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jul-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jul-build-update/</guid><description>A July build update Windows are in!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Working on the water pooling solution What’s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done July has been window month. We are pretty proud to say that we&amp;rsquo;ve now got our hand made windows installed 🙂 - here is how it went!
We began with the bathroom window, which we thought would be a breeze. However, not even one window down we faced our first hiccup - it turns out the width of the window frame was not wide enough to run flush with the internal lining of the tiny house (on the inside) and flush with the exterior cladding on the outside.</description></item><item><title>June Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jun-build-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jun-build-update/</guid><description>A June build update A lot of shopping and finally finishing sanding the cladding!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done The tail end of May and the month of June have been quite eventful, filled with a lot of shopping and unexpected visitors from far away states. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in!
Our fanciest acquisition was a package of flathead brass screws that arrived in the mail.</description></item><item><title>May Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-may-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-may-build-update/</guid><description>An May build update Wrapping the tiny house like a present 🎁🎁🎁
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Hello, hello! As May rolls on, the days are getting shorter, and our productivity has slowed down. Not to make this blog become a Let's complain about the weather blog, but with the weather changing, we&amp;rsquo;ve had to battle with the elements to get any work done. Sunny weekdays are always followed by rainy weekends, leaving us only a few good hours to work on our project.</description></item><item><title>April Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-apr-build-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-apr-build-update/</guid><description>An April build update We got some walls up!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done A timeline of sorts What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What a hectic last few days! Erny and I took some time off to focus on the tiny house full-time over the Easter break. For us, the past week has been a rollercoaster ride of highs and lows, with the weather constantly threatening to rain on our parade.</description></item><item><title>March Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/mar-2023-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/mar-2023-build-update/</guid><description>A March build update A door, some floor progress and general reflections.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Hello from The Miette HQ! The last half of February and March has been a busy and productive month for Erny and Lys, and thanks to an unseasonably dry month on the coast we have made some great progress on the tiny.
We kicked off the month by refurbishing our 40-year-old door.</description></item><item><title>How To Build a Window</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/how-to-build-a-window/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/how-to-build-a-window/</guid><description>Just a short update - Lys put together a little montage of our window building journey (over 8 months in the making) and we have started tackling the doors! Will update our door journey in the next post but for now enjoy the video!
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny</description></item><item><title>January Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/jan-2023-build-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/jan-2023-build-update/</guid><description>A January build update We get glass in window frames.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done In December last year Lys&amp;rsquo; parents gently highlighted that they want their garage back. So, with a deadline of September 30th and some wonderful sunshine we decided to nail these windows down. Honestly, we try write these blogs once a month but sometimes its difficult to encapsulate every trial and tribulation when you cannot even begin to remember them all.</description></item><item><title>November December Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/nov-dec-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/nov-dec-2022-build-update/</guid><description>An November December build update Window making continues with a side of weddings, berry farms, and other sundry end of year activities.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done So while writing this blog post, Lys discovers there&amp;rsquo;s a frisbee emoji 🥏 also known as the flying disc emoji - how random! Tiny house wise though - our journey continues working on our windows.</description></item><item><title>Oct Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/oct-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/oct-2022-build-update/</guid><description>An October build update We got solar! ☀️ ☀️ ☀️
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done One of our neighbours decided to demolish their house without removing their 10 year old solar system (it was not cost effective for them to re-install). Luckily for us they said that if we could take it down we could have it! Erny clambered onto the roof on a balmy Sunday day to bring the panels down.</description></item><item><title>August September 2022 Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 13:54:47 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</guid><description>An August September build update Hello Spring! Working almost every weekend, these last two months we&amp;rsquo;ve actually got a proper build update &amp;#x1f604;.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done We went through our stash of 90x45mm lengths and picked out roof rafters. These have been measured down to a 20 degree angle and some have been cut to size! We&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this in the garage when there has been a rain shower break and it has worked quite well.</description></item><item><title>Operation Find a Roof</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/operation-find-a-roof/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 19:26:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/operation-find-a-roof/</guid><description>Operation Find a Roof As Lys sits down to write this she can officially say that we have sourced all of our roof components! It is a mixture of second hand material and some first-hand non-negotiable(s) but it&amp;rsquo;s great to finally have all the bits and bobs.
Table Of Contents The Design The Material Gutters Sundry Items The Design We chose to have a slightly off centred gable roof for our tiny house.</description></item><item><title>July 2022 Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/july-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 20:15:04 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/july-2022-build-update/</guid><description>A July build update What have we done? Absolutely nothing. Lys honestly thinks it&amp;rsquo;s been the wettest July that we&amp;rsquo;ve lived through in sunny Australia.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Erny jetted off to the US for a few weeks to play ultimate frisbee! Left to her own devices Lys did a few sundry things like source suppliers for our metal connectors. We&amp;rsquo;ve also added a few new features to the site - now you can add comments and now subscribe if you feel so inclined.</description></item><item><title>A Quick Trip to Canberra</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/a-quick-trip-to-canberra/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 19:26:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/a-quick-trip-to-canberra/</guid><description>A quick trip to Canberra In January we sped down to Canberra to pick up some double glazed glass for our windows. We had been on the hunt for double glazed glass closer to home but it seems that Canberra - having cold winters - has great reclaimed glass options.
Table Of Contents Introducing Handyman Trading Post A side step antiquing So what&amp;rsquo;d you get? But why use double glazing?</description></item><item><title>June 2022 Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/june-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 23:15:04 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/june-2022-build-update/</guid><description>A June build update Decided that we should do monthly build updates as we march towards the end of the year. We&amp;rsquo;re hoping to reach lock up by then (walls, floor and roof complete) and 31st December is our D-day.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Erny bought a second hand table saw for $400 a few months back and it&amp;rsquo;s been an absolute workhorse.</description></item><item><title>Hi I'm Miette</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/hi-im-miette/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 17:41:24 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/hi-im-miette/</guid><description>Hello World &amp;#x1f44b; My name is Lys and my partner Erny and I are building a tiny home made out of seconds, reclaimed and recycled materials. This is a small space on the interwebs to to document our progress and share our photos for anyone who would like to follow our journey! &amp;#x1f604;
Table Of Contents Why build a tiny house? Do you have any constraints? What does miette mean? So how&amp;rsquo;s it going?</description></item></channel></rss>