<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>windows on The Miette</title>
    <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in windows on The Miette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 11:08:26 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>November December Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/nov-dec-2022-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/nov-dec-2022-build-update/</guid>
      <description>An November December build update Window making continues with a side of weddings, berry farms, and other sundry end of year activities.
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done So while writing this blog post, Lys discovers there&amp;rsquo;s a frisbee emoji 🥏 also known as the flying disc emoji - how random! Tiny house wise though - our journey continues working on our windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oct Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/oct-2022-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/oct-2022-build-update/</guid>
      <description>An October build update We got solar! ☀️ ☀️ ☀️
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done One of our neighbours decided to demolish their house without removing their 10 year old solar system (it was not cost effective for them to re-install). Luckily for us they said that if we could take it down we could have it! Erny clambered onto the roof on a balmy Sunday day to bring the panels down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August September 2022 Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 13:54:47 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</guid>
      <description>An August September build update Hello Spring! Working almost every weekend, these last two months we&amp;rsquo;ve actually got a proper build update 😄.
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done We went through our stash of 90x45mm lengths and picked out roof rafters. These have been measured down to a 20 degree angle and some have been cut to size! We&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this in the garage when there has been a rain shower break and it has worked quite well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Trip to Canberra</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/a-quick-trip-to-canberra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 19:26:12 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/a-quick-trip-to-canberra/</guid>
      <description>A quick trip to Canberra In January we sped down to Canberra to pick up some double glazed glass for our windows. We had been on the hunt for double glazed glass closer to home but it seems that Canberra - having cold winters - has great reclaimed glass options.
Table Of ContentsIntroducing Handyman Trading Post A side step antiquing So what&amp;rsquo;d you get? But why use double glazing?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
