<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>holiday on The Miette</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/holiday/</link><description>Recent content in holiday on The Miette</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:08:26 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/holiday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>September October Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</guid><description>A September holiday and an October build update 👋 Well hello there! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since our last blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy exploring the big wild world. Back on home soil we crack on with cladding the house 🏠
Table Of Contents What we returned to in October What’s next? The past months have been a whirlwind of adventure, starting with a journey to the United States for a wedding - congratulations Visrut and Ruhani!</description></item><item><title>August Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-aug-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-aug-build-update/</guid><description>An August build update Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done An aside about our skylight flashing The concept of a 1.5 person job We&amp;rsquo;re back with another exciting update from our construction escapades. August has been a whirlwind of challenges, cleaning, and mad dash purchases but we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to make some significant roofing progress on our tiny house. Buckle up, because we&amp;rsquo;ve got quite the adventure to share!
What we&amp;rsquo;ve done As we kicked off August, we found ourselves juggling two passions: our relentless dedication to our tiny house project (read as: desperation to finish the roof before we leave for the US) and the thrilling tension of the Women&amp;rsquo;s World Cup (go the Matildas!</description></item></channel></rss>