<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>holiday on The Miette</title>
    <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/holiday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in holiday on The Miette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 13:04:21 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/holiday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>April and May Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-apr-may-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 13:04:21 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-apr-may-build-update/</guid>
      <description>My goodness hasn’t it been a time — feels like we haven’t written a post in a long time. Looking back, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe how quickly time has flown by. April and May seem like distant memories, and now, here we are, well into&amp;hellip;July. But we haven’t been sleeping and not working — let me take you through the latest updates and progress we&amp;rsquo;ve made during these transformative months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Update For 2023</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-final-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-final-build-update/</guid>
      <description>Our Last 2023 Build Update Hello and happy new year! We hope your break was filled with relaxation and joy. Ours was a mix of hard work and a few breakthroughs in our tiny house project. Let&amp;rsquo;s catch you up on our latest adventures.
Table Of ContentsChristmas Chronicles Welcoming the New Year with Wall #3 January Goals What&amp;rsquo;s next? Christmas Chronicles Did anyone experience hail in your area? We were, once again, in a relentless race against daylight and unpredictable weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-nov-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-nov-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A November build update Greetings from our ever-evolving construction site! November has been a month of highs, lows, and, of course, more cladding adventures. So, grab your virtual hard hat, and let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the nitty-gritty details.
Table Of ContentsMaking Our Soffits Pretty (and giving us headaches) What’s next? Our journey begins with drumroll… putting finishing touches on a wall, and oh, what a journey it has been. The internal debate raged on: to cover the corner where cladding meets, should we go with Surfmist steel corner flashing or the charm of contrasting wood trim?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September October Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A September holiday and an October build update 👋 Well hello there! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since our last blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy exploring the big wild world. Back on home soil we crack on with cladding the house 🏠
Table Of ContentsWhat we returned to in October What’s next? The past months have been a whirlwind of adventure, starting with a journey to the United States for a wedding - congratulations Visrut and Ruhani!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-aug-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-aug-build-update/</guid>
      <description>An August build update Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done An aside about our skylight flashing The concept of a 1.5 person job We&amp;rsquo;re back with another exciting update from our construction escapades. August has been a whirlwind of challenges, cleaning, and mad dash purchases but we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to make some significant roofing progress on our tiny house. Buckle up, because we&amp;rsquo;ve got quite the adventure to share!
What we&amp;rsquo;ve done As we kicked off August, we found ourselves juggling two passions: our relentless dedication to our tiny house project (read as: desperation to finish the roof before we leave for the US) and the thrilling tension of the Women&amp;rsquo;s World Cup (go the Matildas!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
