<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cladding on The Miette</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/cladding/</link><description>Recent content in cladding on The Miette</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 11:08:26 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/cladding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>July Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jul-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jul-build-update/</guid><description>A July build update Windows are in!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Working on the water pooling solution What’s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done July has been window month. We are pretty proud to say that we&amp;rsquo;ve now got our hand made windows installed 🙂 - here is how it went!
We began with the bathroom window, which we thought would be a breeze. However, not even one window down we faced our first hiccup - it turns out the width of the window frame was not wide enough to run flush with the internal lining of the tiny house (on the inside) and flush with the exterior cladding on the outside.</description></item><item><title>June Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jun-build-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jun-build-update/</guid><description>A June build update A lot of shopping and finally finishing sanding the cladding!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done The tail end of May and the month of June have been quite eventful, filled with a lot of shopping and unexpected visitors from far away states. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in!
Our fanciest acquisition was a package of flathead brass screws that arrived in the mail.</description></item><item><title>August September 2022 Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 13:54:47 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</guid><description>An August September build update Hello Spring! Working almost every weekend, these last two months we&amp;rsquo;ve actually got a proper build update &amp;#x1f604;.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done We went through our stash of 90x45mm lengths and picked out roof rafters. These have been measured down to a 20 degree angle and some have been cut to size! We&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this in the garage when there has been a rain shower break and it has worked quite well.</description></item></channel></rss>