<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cedar on The Miette</title>
    <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/cedar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cedar on The Miette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 11:08:26 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/cedar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>November Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-nov-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-nov-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A November build update Greetings from our ever-evolving construction site! November has been a month of highs, lows, and, of course, more cladding adventures. So, grab your virtual hard hat, and let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the nitty-gritty details.
Table Of ContentsMaking Our Soffits Pretty (and giving us headaches) What’s next? Our journey begins with drumroll… putting finishing touches on a wall, and oh, what a journey it has been. The internal debate raged on: to cover the corner where cladding meets, should we go with Surfmist steel corner flashing or the charm of contrasting wood trim?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September October Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A September holiday and an October build update 👋 Well hello there! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since our last blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy exploring the big wild world. Back on home soil we crack on with cladding the house 🏠
Table Of ContentsWhat we returned to in October What’s next? The past months have been a whirlwind of adventure, starting with a journey to the United States for a wedding - congratulations Visrut and Ruhani!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August September 2022 Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 13:54:47 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</guid>
      <description>An August September build update Hello Spring! Working almost every weekend, these last two months we&amp;rsquo;ve actually got a proper build update 😄.
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done We went through our stash of 90x45mm lengths and picked out roof rafters. These have been measured down to a 20 degree angle and some have been cut to size! We&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this in the garage when there has been a rain shower break and it has worked quite well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
