<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bathroom on The Miette</title>
    <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/bathroom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bathroom on The Miette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 18:56:57 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/bathroom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025 January to May Build Update: Progress, Travel, and Tiny Wins</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2025-january-to-may-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 18:56:57 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2025-january-to-may-build-update/</guid>
      <description>Oh, heyyyy long time no see&amp;hellip;it’s been a little while since we’ve updated you all — five months, to be exact! Between travelling, working, and chipping away at the house, the blog has definitely fallen to the wayside, but we’re back with plenty to share. Let’s dive into what’s been keeping us busy over the past few months. Spoiler alert: we’ve made progress, but as usual our timeline has been blown out of the window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October, November and December Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-oct-nov-dec-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:33:10 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-oct-nov-dec-build-update/</guid>
      <description>Happy 2025! We hope you&amp;rsquo;ve had a restful festive season 🎄🎉. Time doesn’t just fly — it seems to sprint when you’re building a tiny house. Going to pack updates for October, November, and December in this build update, there’s been a lot more construction than reflection and writing. But, as we reminisce on the past three months, it’s clear how much we’ve accomplished, as we continue to chip away at our goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April and May Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-apr-may-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 13:04:21 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-apr-may-build-update/</guid>
      <description>My goodness hasn’t it been a time — feels like we haven’t written a post in a long time. Looking back, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe how quickly time has flown by. April and May seem like distant memories, and now, here we are, well into&amp;hellip;July. But we haven’t been sleeping and not working — let me take you through the latest updates and progress we&amp;rsquo;ve made during these transformative months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
