<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Roof on The Miette</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/roof/</link><description>Recent content in Roof on The Miette</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 11:08:26 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/roof/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>August Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-aug-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-aug-build-update/</guid><description>An August build update Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done An aside about our skylight flashing The concept of a 1.5 person job We&amp;rsquo;re back with another exciting update from our construction escapades. August has been a whirlwind of challenges, cleaning, and mad dash purchases but we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to make some significant roofing progress on our tiny house. Buckle up, because we&amp;rsquo;ve got quite the adventure to share!
What we&amp;rsquo;ve done As we kicked off August, we found ourselves juggling two passions: our relentless dedication to our tiny house project (read as: desperation to finish the roof before we leave for the US) and the thrilling tension of the Women&amp;rsquo;s World Cup (go the Matildas!</description></item><item><title>May Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-may-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-may-build-update/</guid><description>An May build update Wrapping the tiny house like a present 🎁🎁🎁
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Hello, hello! As May rolls on, the days are getting shorter, and our productivity has slowed down. Not to make this blog become a Let's complain about the weather blog, but with the weather changing, we&amp;rsquo;ve had to battle with the elements to get any work done. Sunny weekdays are always followed by rainy weekends, leaving us only a few good hours to work on our project.</description></item><item><title>April Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-apr-build-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-apr-build-update/</guid><description>An April build update We got some walls up!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done A timeline of sorts What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What a hectic last few days! Erny and I took some time off to focus on the tiny house full-time over the Easter break. For us, the past week has been a rollercoaster ride of highs and lows, with the weather constantly threatening to rain on our parade.</description></item><item><title>March Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/mar-2023-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/mar-2023-build-update/</guid><description>A March build update A door, some floor progress and general reflections.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Hello from The Miette HQ! The last half of February and March has been a busy and productive month for Erny and Lys, and thanks to an unseasonably dry month on the coast we have made some great progress on the tiny.
We kicked off the month by refurbishing our 40-year-old door.</description></item></channel></rss>