<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Insulation on The Miette</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/insulation/</link><description>Recent content in Insulation on The Miette</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:20:37 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/insulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>June July Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-june-july-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:20:37 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-june-july-build-update/</guid><description>Hello! It’s another double month build update, not by design but by necessity as we have been working hard to make this tiny house more of a reality. June saw us work on our kitchen cabinets while we wait for the professionals and buying an HRV system, and July saw us getting all our insulation done! We watched many hours of Tour de France and as Lys writes this the Olympics is on in the background, so we are feeling very inspired watching others achieve their goals.</description></item><item><title>February and March Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-feb-mar-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 14:51:27 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-feb-mar-build-update/</guid><description>Well hello there, long time no write. Not really sure where all the time went, but let’s start in February and make our way through the months, shall we?
Table Of Contents February - Breaks and Supply Chain Delays March Easter Build-Athlon What&amp;rsquo;s next? February - Breaks and Supply Chain Delays To begin, in February, our tiny house project took a bit of a breather, allowing us to indulge in some personal pursuits.</description></item><item><title>May Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-may-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-may-build-update/</guid><description>An May build update Wrapping the tiny house like a present 🎁🎁🎁
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Hello, hello! As May rolls on, the days are getting shorter, and our productivity has slowed down. Not to make this blog become a Let's complain about the weather blog, but with the weather changing, we&amp;rsquo;ve had to battle with the elements to get any work done. Sunny weekdays are always followed by rainy weekends, leaving us only a few good hours to work on our project.</description></item></channel></rss>