<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on The Miette</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on The Miette</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 11:08:26 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Final Update For 2023</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-final-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-final-build-update/</guid><description>Our Last 2023 Build Update Hello and happy new year! We hope your break was filled with relaxation and joy. Ours was a mix of hard work and a few breakthroughs in our tiny house project. Let&amp;rsquo;s catch you up on our latest adventures.
Table Of Contents Christmas Chronicles Welcoming the New Year with Wall #3 January Goals What&amp;rsquo;s next? Christmas Chronicles Did anyone experience hail in your area? We were, once again, in a relentless race against daylight and unpredictable weather. The elements threw everything at us, from rain to scorching 40-degree days, and even a hail spell! Erny spent most of the break looking at the Weatherzone app to make sure we would always be in the clear. Even with these curveballs, over Christmas, our tiny house saw significant progress.
Hail in summer
Starting the third wall
We successfully completed the long wall — a cause to pop some champagne (or whatever beverage of your choice may be). Installing weatherboards around the window proved particularly tricky, adding an extra layer of complexity as we ascended. We had to cut the boards to size fitting around the window, but each weatherboard has its own twists and bows, so everything needed to be custom fit. The higher we climbed on our ladders, the more demanding the installation process became.
Using the circular saw to fit the boards around
A pleasant December surprise came in the form of a visit from Silvia and Amanda, who came by to provide some moral support. Amanda is taking a hand tools course, a skill set that, in hindsight, we realised would have been incredibly useful at the beginning of our project. Lesson learned for future builders!
To finish off the wall and prepare for the upcoming gutter installation, we invested in custom-made flashing. Installing this was difficult and very finicky. We needed to cut down our corners to size and redo some of the roof! The result not only looked impressive but also offered a sigh of relief as the wall&amp;rsquo;s completion meant less tarping to protect against rain. Throughout Christmas, we must have tarped the house over 5 times. A clever addition to enhance stability was the introduction of two pop rivets in the center of the flashing (this was a Lys brainwave). These keeps the pieces in place and flush too to the wall.
Install brass screws
Welcoming the New Year with Wall #3 After a short escape down South, our focus shifted to the third wall, and this time around, the process has been notably smoother. Erny&amp;rsquo;s honed skill in accurately cutting each weatherboard to size, considering the timber&amp;rsquo;s twists and turns, has streamlined the workflow. With a helping hand from Bel, who assisted with adding battens and oiling the cladding ends. It’s always so nice to have friends come around. Even the soffits went up seamlessly, a stark contrast to the challenges faced during the first wall installation. Our first soffit took over a weekend, but this soffit took less than half a day.
Cleaning our surfmist colorbond roof
January Goals While undoubtedly tiring, the satisfaction of making sustained progress over the break has been immensely rewarding. The longer days of summer have certainly worked in our favour. Upon reflection, we have also learnt a considerable amount about ourselves. Erny is a perfectionist, and slight cosmetic flaws bug him to the nth degree. Lys really likes to see progress and is sometimes too one-track minded. Because of this, our estimation skills have become more grounded, perhaps more realistic, as we&amp;rsquo;ve navigated the intricacies of tiny house construction.
We also have an expanding toolkit of technical skills (get it!). Lys can now confidently wield the table saw, and Erny is a circular saw fiend. He even took the circular saw to work to fix some monitor stands! It is so rewarding gaining some level of mastery, if not amateur confidence, to build something that you once dreamed of.
Unfortunately, we did not manage to finish the exterior by the 31st December — so we’re trying our luck for the end of January. Simultaneously, we are contemplating simplifying the interior design. The joking request to move in by Christmas 2024 has spurred this consideration – apparently, the family prefers relaxation over the new year&amp;rsquo;s break instead of holding ladders!
Lys&amp;rsquo; brother helpig out
What&amp;rsquo;s next? A heartfelt “Thank You” goes out to our family &amp;amp; friends – Dan, Troy, Michael, Jason, Silvia, and Bel – whose unwavering support has made this endeavour not just manageable but enjoyable. Bel, in particular, has been quick to remind us to document our progress and celebrate wins. With this in mind — we can’t garuntee more documented progress but hopefully we will do more celebrating in 2024!
Here is to a constructive 2024! Thanks for reading and catch ya later 😄
Happy New Year!</description><category>build_update</category><category>tiny_house</category><category>holiday</category><category>cladding</category><category>walls</category><category>cedar</category></item><item><title>November Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-nov-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-nov-build-update/</guid><description>A November build update Greetings from our ever-evolving construction site! November has been a month of highs, lows, and, of course, more cladding adventures. So, grab your virtual hard hat, and let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the nitty-gritty details.
Table Of Contents Making Our Soffits Pretty (and giving us headaches) What’s next? Our journey begins with drumroll… putting finishing touches on a wall, and oh, what a journey it has been. The internal debate raged on: to cover the corner where cladding meets, should we go with Surfmist steel corner flashing or the charm of contrasting wood trim? In the end, the warmth of wood won us over, embracing its subtle curves and warps over time. We kicked things off by cutting and installing some Douglas fir corners. It might not be as durable as steel, but it looks undeniably great! These corners were definitely a challenge to install as we started using those beautiful yet painful brass screws. We bought these in June if you, dear reader, remember and now making they were grand debut.
But alas, the pain set early — they kept slipping out of the drill bit, and they&amp;rsquo;re not self-tapping, and they need to be counter-sunk. All this compounded and added an extra layer of complexity for the installation. Silvia and Deniz, our wise friends, had warned us (read as Lys), and now we understand why. Flat head screws are so finicky! Even screwing just 18 screws (1.8% of the total screws that we have to install), the head of the impact driver played hard to get, slipping here and there, and the softer brass demanded careful handling to avoid dents. Yet, the end result? A visually stunning contrast of gold brass against the warm tones of our orange wood – a classic combination that&amp;rsquo;s hard to beat.
With corners and battens securely in place, we turned our attention to installing the first set of cladding: discarded pine weatherboards Erny unearthed from a previous build — for free no less! Grime-covered and weathered, these boards had seen better days. After a thorough cleaning, we painstakingly measured, painted the ends, and aligned them with precision. Lys, at this point, was starting to appreciate why some opt for the simplicity of Colorbond wall cladding. It took us 4 days to clad the far wall, and we puttied all the screw holes and sanded everything down ready for paint!
Starting to add cladding
Making Our Soffits Pretty (and giving us headaches) Just as we thought we had conquered the wall, the realisation hit – completing the soffit was crucial for that clean finish. Our November goal shifted gears from “Let&amp;rsquo;s clad this wall!” to “We have to defeat this soffit!”. Luckily we had some cedar ship lap, saved from landfill earlier in the year. It was too short to be installed on a wall, but was the perfect size for the soffit. Cedar is also light, termite-resistant, and antifungal, so it is a great cladding option. Installing these small cedar pieces posed a challenge, especially high up on the ladder with a vertical drill. Our neck muscles got a workout, and it was a bit painful to look up, but teamwork prevailed. Lys handled drilling and pilot holes on the ground below, Erny took charge of installation, and after a few miscommunications, everything eventually fell into place.
Preparing the brass screws for installation
Installing the soffit
Now, onto the long back wall, the one with the fewest windows but its own set of challenges. On a 30-degree Sunday, Bel joined the crew, installing the lower half of the battens while Erny and Lys focused on the corner. Then we managed to get our first four weatherboards onto the house. Workflow became smoother; brass screws on the corner once again looked slick, and this time the installation was less painful. Silva had recommended using a screw guide, and this was a godsend. There is a sheath that goes over the screw and keeps it from slipping. It is a bit disconcerting because you can&amp;rsquo;t see the head of the screw, however, we are slowly getting the hang of it. We&amp;rsquo;ve also purchased a screwdriver with magnetic interchangeable heads, which has allowed us to make the screw head slots vertical. It&amp;rsquo;s very satisfying hand finishing the screws, however it is a bit of a labour of love. On the topic of labour, Bel suggested that we line up the pine cladding with the cedar cladding at the corner, for a seamless look. This means that we&amp;rsquo;ll have to use a few extra boards, but we think we&amp;rsquo;ll have enough resources. Only time will tell on this one…
Starting the long wall with the western red cedar
What’s next? There is still so much to do on the tiny house if we want to get to lock up by the 31st. We are currently focusing on the back wall, however we still need to find a correctly sized deadlock for the door, and we also need to create a door jamb. The clock is ticking! 🛠️🏡
One wall basically done and ready for paint!</description><category>build_update</category><category>tiny_house</category><category>holiday</category><category>cladding</category><category>cedar</category></item><item><title>September October Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-sep-oct-build-update/</guid><description>A September holiday and an October build update 👋 Well hello there! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since our last blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy exploring the big wild world. Back on home soil we crack on with cladding the house 🏠
Table Of Contents What we returned to in October What’s next? The past months have been a whirlwind of adventure, starting with a journey to the United States for a wedding - congratulations Visrut and Ruhani! We travelled from Australia to the U.S. and embarked on an adventure that took us from the vibrant streets of New Orleans all the way to the iconic city of New York. Along the way, we had the pleasure of exploring the stunning natural beauty of the Smoky Mountains National Park. Our hike along a small section of the Appalachian Trail was a definite highlight. A huge shout-out to Kat, Erny&amp;rsquo;s frisbee friend, for being our guide and teaching us about hemlock, spruce, and fir trees.
We also stayed in a teeny tiny house in Asheville, NC. It was hand made and very much inspired by Jay Shafer, author of The Small House Book. We&amp;rsquo;ve stayed in a few tiny houses now and this one was filled with wood, wonderful books and was smaller than ours (sitting at a pretty 9.1 square meters)! You can find their listing on Airbnb here.
Rustic and very blue exterior
Cute roof design
Look at that wooden interior of the tiny house
Tiny kitchen
What we returned to in October Upon our return, however, we were met with an unexpected challenge. The cladding we had lovingly oiled for our tiny house had begun to turn green. Naturally, we (read Lys only) were distressed and initially suspected it was mould. Spot cleaning efforts were in vain, prompting us to seek assistance from the helpful Cutek Oil team. They enlightened us about a copper additive in the oil that can, on rare occasions, cause light-coloured wood to turn green. Apparently they don&amp;rsquo;t see this happen often - luck was not on our side, and we were among the &amp;ldquo;unlucky&amp;rdquo; few. The good news is that this greenish tint should fade over time. If we&amp;rsquo;re feeling impatient, we can opt for an acidic wash to expedite the process. We&amp;rsquo;re still contemplating our next steps, but it&amp;rsquo;s a relief to know that our cladding isn&amp;rsquo;t harbouring mould.
Small freak outs as the cedar turns green
The acid wash cleans the green hue off excellently
Our construction efforts continue, with a focus on cladding the short wall of our tiny house (with pine weatherboards that Erny got for free). Achieving a level finish has proven to be quite the challenge, and our workflow is deliberate and time-consuming. Each piece requires custom cutting to accommodate the picture window, painting of the ends, a patient wait for them to dry, and meticulous pre-drilling of holes before the final installation. It&amp;rsquo;s a labour of love, but with each addition, our tiny house is taking on the appearance of a true home. It&amp;rsquo;s also the final layer of protection, giving our hard-working sisalation a well-deserved break.
Adding battens
Starting to clad the wall
Working late into the night
What’s next? All in all, it&amp;rsquo;s been pretty slow-going. Our goal is to complete the exterior of the house by the end of the year, with December 31st being our unofficial deadline. We&amp;rsquo;ve got a few hurdles to solve like what sort of lock we&amp;rsquo;ll use on our vintage French doors (a problem we&amp;rsquo;ve been procrastinating on) and installing over 1000 flat head screws. However, life has a way of throwing delightful distractions our way, like Christmas parties, weddings, and celebrations. We shall see!
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny
Our USA Trip in a photo</description><category>build_update</category><category>tiny_house</category><category>holiday</category><category>cladding</category><category>cedar</category></item><item><title>August Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-aug-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-aug-build-update/</guid><description>An August build update Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done An aside about our skylight flashing The concept of a 1.5 person job We&amp;rsquo;re back with another exciting update from our construction escapades. August has been a whirlwind of challenges, cleaning, and mad dash purchases but we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to make some significant roofing progress on our tiny house. Buckle up, because we&amp;rsquo;ve got quite the adventure to share!
What we&amp;rsquo;ve done As we kicked off August, we found ourselves juggling two passions: our relentless dedication to our tiny house project (read as: desperation to finish the roof before we leave for the US) and the thrilling tension of the Women&amp;rsquo;s World Cup (go the Matildas!). Our multitasking skills were put to the test as we cheered for our favourite teams while meticulously measuring and constructing.
Firstly, we spent an absolute age on a cleaning mission, Our surf mist colorbond, which we had purchased from a finished renovation on the Central Coast had been sitting in the garden for quite a while gathering leaves, dirt and the occasional leech. Armed with water pressure and determination, we worked to restore these pieces to their former shining glory (in some sense quite literally - the surf mist colour really reflects the sun). Note to self - store your materials properly to avoid having to clean them when you need them 8 months later.
Cleaning our surfmist colorbond roof
Installing battens
August also saw Lys stepping into the role of an angle grinder enthusiast. Armed with everyday tools - a sharpie and a bed slat - she tackled the task of precision cutting our roof pieces to size. Bricks played a supporting role, steadying the pieces and she has worked up quite a technique. Meanwhile, Erny did an amazing job installing the battens onto the roof. It was a bit of a trial and error process to cut and then install. We definitely believe he has nerves of steel, because he was definitely quite high up on the ladder. Things were going well&amp;hellip;until an ordering mishap. The roof screws we had initially ordered were too long (50 mm), posing a potential water leakage risk - what a disaster. This really took the wind out of our sails.
In a moment of quick thinking, we devised several solutions:
Use the screws that we had and risk the water (no thank you) Buy 200 screws in the correct colour from a supplier in melbourne (we need 250) Buy 1000 screws in the correct colour but no neoprene washer from a supplier in perth (once again we only need 250!) Buy 250 screws from bunnings and spray paint the tops in the correct colour Ultimately, we decided on the last minute dash to Bunnings (you&amp;rsquo;ll soon notice a last-minute dash to Bunnings theme in August). There, we secured shorter screws and spray paint to camouflage their tops with the roof. This task also introduced Lys to the oddly satisfying world of spray painting. Bar this slight calamity, the long side of the roof went on without a hitch (all of Erny&amp;rsquo;s hard work). The battens were installed quickly, the colorbond was cut to the correct size and we powered through the install - things were looking good. We were ready for the more complex shorter side!
Mad dash to bunnings to buy spray paint
Spray painting the tops of the screws
One side of the roof looking good!
Erny working very hard
We were feeling pretty confident about installing the skylights and the flashing because it&amp;rsquo;s the first item that we&amp;rsquo;ve bought new that&amp;rsquo;s come with manufacturer instructions - think IKEA flat pack instructions on steroids. What we forgot was how heavy the skylights were. Tentatively, under the watchful eye of Lys&amp;rsquo; parents we hauled up the skylights 4 meters up and onto the roof. We then were ready for the flashing until Erny discovered that the flashing was too large for our roof! We made some slight modifications - trimming the metal to size and fiddling with the bottom edge - hopefully the changes won&amp;rsquo;t impact the water draining qualities but that remains to be seen. We also added extra roofing underlay under the flashing to wick water away but an unexpected rain shower during installation forced a hasty application. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a flawless job, but Lys&amp;rsquo; excuse was a battle with laryngitis – and something is better than nothing right? Our hypothesis was soon tested with a 40 mm deluge - the skylights seem to be okay so we are confident that our waterproofing skills can handle more than a little bit of rain.
One skylight in!
An aside about our skylight flashing We don&amp;rsquo;t know if we have written about this before but we actually bought our skylights a few months back from a nice man on the beaches. Unfortunately for us, he had a tiled roof but we were installing a colorbond roof and his roofer had removed a piece of cladding flashing away. This part is pretty important when it comes to water proofing&amp;hellip;And thus began a wild goose chase finding a Velux supplier who would sell us this spare part (we touch upon this on our June Build Update).
We finally found a team in June who could source the parts from Velux, and we went to pick them up after 3 weeks of the order being lost, but then - it turned out Velux had delivered the incorrect part! We contacted the supplier who worked with Velux to deliver us our correct part 2 weeks later. We got the part back home - pretty relieved - only to realise that they did not provide us with enough screws for the full install. We just cut our losses and installed the cladding without the screws for now but we will need to pop our own in - what a journey!
Yet more hurdles awaited, with colorbond panels somehow ending up 8 cm too short. We were so sure that we had measured twice to cut once - but clearly we must have misread the tape measure&amp;hellip;twice. Fortunately, the ridge capping came to the rescue, concealing the discrepancy while still remaining watertight. We decided to push forward with the colorbond install and not re-cut new pieces. This was a good decision - by the time the weekend over we had the skylights in and the second half of the colorbond installed - what an achievement! We were so close to completing the roof, or so we thought.
Installing the short pieces of colorbond
Alas, the construction journey remains an ever-evolving learning curve. Our path took an unexpected turn when we realized that fascia would be a necessary addition before installing the ridge capping – a future problem that suddenly required immediate attention. Originally we had been hoping to install the ridge capping first and leave the eaves until later. This wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have worked aesthetically as the ridge cap needs to be the final piece installed (think of it like the cherry on top of the ice cream Sunday). We would like to thank Metal Roofing Online Roofing tutorials for helping us avoid a potential aesthetic roofing faux pas.
Quick thinking and a pay to win attitude led us to purchase pre-primed fascia from Bunnings, with an added layer of convenience in having the pieces cut to size by the helpful staff. A slight consolation was that we saved $3 dollars as he didn&amp;rsquo;t charge us for the cuts (apparently it&amp;rsquo;s actually $1 a cut at Bunnings). We also needed to buy a pop rivet gun - a tool we had hoped to hire - since we had just ran out of time.
Lys got to work painting the pieces in surfmist, as Erny crafted angles to cut the pieces but we faced yet another challenge – ensuring that barge capping would align seamlessly with our varied cladding designs. We halted the build to labour on the problem with Erny uncovering more problems. This intricate process demanded meticulous mathematical calculations, quite a bit of trigonometry and an abundance of patience. We think we have a plan (it involves purchasing a different style of metal cladding) but it&amp;rsquo;s a puzzle we&amp;rsquo;ll continue to solve as we progress, post our planned US trip. We also battled a new product called butyl tape. This tape is like bluetac on steroids - it sticks to everything in sight! We also learnt that it&amp;rsquo;s harder to work with as the ambient air temperature cools - something we discovered as we were racing against the afternoon sun. Bar the maths and the stickiness, the install went very well and it we are quite pleased with our handy work! The barge capping over the eave really adds to the feel of the house and we are quite pleased with our colour choice.
Late night whiteboard maths to make sure everything fits under the height limit
Painting the facia board
Cutting facia to size
As we observe the barge capping, fascia, and the evolving roof of our tiny house, we acknowledge that while it might not be perfect, it certainly holds character. A friend with experience in construction aptly put it: &amp;ldquo;If you look at fully constructed houses, it never looks perfect. I guarantee you 9.8/10 people won&amp;rsquo;t be able to tell. But you never notice because it&amp;rsquo;s all chaos which falls into a nice harmony.&amp;rdquo; We are taking comfort in the very statistically accurate 9.8 people who won&amp;rsquo;t notice the minor flaws in our install and grateful for friends who know just the right things to say 💕.
It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a tiny house build without a fancy sandwich with fancy local bakery bread
The concept of a 1.5 person job As our project has progressed, we have come to terms with the reality of &amp;ldquo;1.5 person jobs.&amp;rdquo; Holding ladders, passing tools, and lending that extra hand often require the skills of half a person – the unsung hero of construction teams. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a lack of tools or the absence of the perfect clamp, we learned that embracing teamwork is essential for efficient progress. It&amp;rsquo;s also a reminder that as a duo, we can&amp;rsquo;t always maximize efficiency, and that&amp;rsquo;s perfectly acceptable.We&amp;rsquo;re work shopping it 🙂
Anyway - it&amp;rsquo;s been a huge roof building month and it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a quiet September - we&amp;rsquo;re going on holiday! So we will see you soon ✈️
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny
Roof is on!</description><category>build_update</category><category>roof</category><category>tiny_house</category><category>holiday</category></item><item><title>July Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jul-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jul-build-update/</guid><description>A July build update Windows are in!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Working on the water pooling solution What’s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done July has been window month. We are pretty proud to say that we&amp;rsquo;ve now got our hand made windows installed 🙂 - here is how it went!
We began with the bathroom window, which we thought would be a breeze. However, not even one window down we faced our first hiccup - it turns out the width of the window frame was not wide enough to run flush with the internal lining of the tiny house (on the inside) and flush with the exterior cladding on the outside. We were 8 mm short! Talk about a stressful first window weekend. After some deliberation we decided that we would cut an angle into our internal lining and make it a feature. This means that the exterior cladding will be flush giving a more waterproof seal, and we will have to get creative when we tackle the interior. Bar this - the bathroom window went in without a hitch!
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, our workflow largely ran like this:
Lys, armed with her father&amp;rsquo;s vintage Stanley knife cut an I shape into the window cavity The edges were then sealed with aluminium tape starting from the bottom sill Vapourseal tape was added to the bottom of the sill to protect it from water and dampcourse was stapled underneath the window rough opening Flashing was stapled to the underside of the window (a step we forgot quite often) and then the heavy window was carefully lifted and wriggled into position Erny precisely packed the window to make it level and plumb whilst Lys got an arm work out holding the window in place A few screws and swears later the window would be finally in place 🙂 Finish off the flashing by sealing the sides with Vapourseal and stapling in more dampcourse Install the metal head flashing to the top and rejoice ✨ Prepared flashing corner
Lys measuring the flashing to size
Installing the window
Installed window corner
Feeling inspired, we took on the kitchen window next. It proved to be a little more challenging due to its weight and handling difficulties. In our eagerness to position it, we forgot a crucial piece of vapour-seal on the sill. Lys could only describe her feelings in the form of this GIF.
via GIPHY
Additionally, it started to rain, and we realised another design flaw - water was pulling on our opening windows - a slight problem&amp;hellip; Adapting to the situation, we decided to continue with the other fixed window (the picture window) and work on a solution for the water pooling for the opening windows. Then we decided to circle back to fix the kitchen window when we have the resources, the theory being that by the time we have finished installing the other windows, we would have improved our flashing skills with each installation giving us confidence to fix our original mistakes.
Working on the water pooling solution To ensure the opening windows function perfectly and no longer pool during rain, we routed new channels and a slope into the frame. Erny&amp;rsquo;s patience and diligence with the router truly paid off during this process. During this time he broke all four 3 mm router bits! This was due to the Blackbutt timber being so hard. Here we learnt that router bits are way more expensive than drill bits and other wood work accessories.
The four broken bits
The routered drip edge
Erny working with the router
Then, we had a minor router accident while working on the second loft window - somehow we veered the router off course and created a gouge in the lip of the window. We were a little frustrated with ourselves - at this point in July it felt like this window install was facing problem after problem. Determined not to be discouraged, Erny glued a piece back in and sanded it down to fit seamlessly with the new slope (if you don&amp;rsquo;t look too closely you don&amp;rsquo;t actually notice it) and besides, it will be 3 meters in the air, so it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t affect the aesthetics of the house dramatically. Guess there is nothing wood glue and putty can&amp;rsquo;t solve! 😄
Fixing the routered gouge
Back on course we roped the whole family together and installed our big picture window. This window is HUUUGEEEE and needs three people to carry it. The installation was pretty stressful but now that it is in it looks fantastic. The abundance of natural light is a delightful preview of the warm moments we&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy once our tiny house is complete. Lys keeps talking about how she&amp;rsquo;s excited to have a cup of tea looking out of the window - and that vision is slowly getting closer and closer.
Flashing the large window cavity
Installing the picture window
Lots of light in the tiny house
Our last weekend on window duty really highlighted that we needed a break. It was slow-going, and we encountered a few mishaps. While installing the final loft window, Lys accidentally broke a beloved bee teacup when she tipped the staple gun slipped off a ladder. As we fixed the kitchen window Erny faced a few frustrations installing the last two windows with the Blackbutt timber tearing out. A few swears were definitely said in a multitude of languages. Despite these moments, we&amp;rsquo;re learning to embrace the imperfections and relish the character they bring to our tiny house. We&amp;rsquo;ve lost count of the amount of times we&amp;rsquo;ve consoled ourselves saying &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a feature, not a flaw&amp;rdquo;.
Racing against the light to install our windows
As we look back on our experiences this month, we&amp;rsquo;ve learned some valuable lessons:
Small eaves can make a significant difference in both aesthetics and weather protection. It rained a bit throughout the process and we discovered our windows that had a little eave were by far more protected than the windows on the long sides. We&amp;rsquo;re definitely on the hunt now to install the gutters and roof. Custom window building is best left to the experts to avoid potential hiccups. (Lys vows to never do this again but concedes that we have learnt a lot) Borrowing tools from a well-stocked tool library can save the day. We&amp;rsquo;re really trying to avoid buying more tools and having a membership with the tool library has been a lifesaver! This time around we rented the staple gun (which came with complementary staples). It feels great to reduce costs and put these tools to work - a definite recommendation for anyone a bit tight on space but wants to dabble in DIY. Staple gun from the tool library
What’s next? In a slight addendum, we&amp;rsquo;ve also finished oiling our cladding! What a milestone. We&amp;rsquo;re delighted with the progress we&amp;rsquo;ve made and are excited to continue our tiny house adventure - next month is roof month so definitely more problem solving on the horizon&amp;hellip;
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny
Smiles all around because the windows are in</description><category>build_update</category><category>cladding</category><category>oiling</category><category>window</category><category>tiny_house</category><category>router</category></item><item><title>June Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jun-build-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jun-build-update/</guid><description>A June build update A lot of shopping and finally finishing sanding the cladding!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done The tail end of May and the month of June have been quite eventful, filled with a lot of shopping and unexpected visitors from far away states. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in!
Our fanciest acquisition was a package of flathead brass screws that arrived in the mail. While elegant in appearance, they present a formidable challenge due to their soft composition and that flatheads are known for slipping and causing drills to gouge the timber. Every person that Lys shares this purchase with is flabbergasted on the screw choice - why pick something so challenging to work with? It turns out that inspiration can strike at any moment, and Lys found hers while passing through a fancy neighbourhood. She spotted a garage door adorned with western red cedar facing and beautiful brass nails. The sight left a lasting impression, but clearly Lys didn&amp;rsquo;t realise exactly what she was getting into&amp;hellip;we will see how we fare.
Our very expensive flathead screws
Decking oil also made its way to our doorstep (all the way from Western Australia), and we wasted no time in starting the oiling process. The product we chose is CUTEK® Extreme CD50, a high-performance, oil-based wood stabiliser with a self-healing effect. This Australian-made solution penetrates deeply into the timber, highlighting its natural grain and beauty while providing robust and long-lasting protection. It is quite nice to use a product built for the harsh Australian climate, but we&amp;rsquo;re trying out a few different oils on this build - it&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see how they age and weather over time.
You can really see the difference between the oiled wood and unoiled pieces
Oiled cladding pieces
However, using CUTEK® Extreme CD50 comes with its own challenges. The rough sawn surface of our wood eagerly absorbs the oil, making it quite the thirsty endeavour. Additionally - it&amp;rsquo;s there has been a cold snap and the oil is taking much longer to penetrate and dry.
Oiled cladding in the drying zone
Oiled cladding close up
To expedite the process and make use of the good weather (read - lack of rain), we enlisted the help of Lys&amp;rsquo; brother, Tom, who proved to be an absolute champion at oiling duty. Having an extra pair of hands certainly makes the work fly by, and we&amp;rsquo;re grateful for his assistance.
Tom working hard oiling the cladding boards over the weekend
Huge thank you to the best brother ever
Finally, our more practical purchase (in an attempt to prepare for the next phase of our project) was dampcourse and flashing tape to flash and waterproof our windows. This will be crucial when the time comes to install them.
A free hat with our flashing tape
Once again we&amp;rsquo;ve been inspired by Two Hands and A Tiny House with his flashing techniques. Lys has lost count how many times we&amp;rsquo;ve paused, played and repeated that video. We have also found these great videos by the Australian Glass and Window Association - the demonstrations are extremely clear and quite detailed.
June also saw some unexpected and helpful visitors! Our team expanded further with the dedication of Bel, Silvia, Lys, and Lys&amp;rsquo; mother, who spent many weekends sanding cedar weatherboards to the correct grit for installation. Together we refurbished and refreshed over 200 lineal meters of cladding starting from 80 grit to then 100 grit and then finally 120 grit. Huge thanks to their hard work and attention to detail.
Tea break when our friends come around
On the logistical front but still in the shopping haul theme, Erny took charge of getting quotes for a missing piece of our skylights. It was a huge relief to discover that the cost would be less than $150, making it a worthwhile investment to give our skylights a new lease on life. We&amp;rsquo;re excited to kick off the roof construction in July, and these skylights will undoubtedly be a fantastic addition. As we progress, - we&amp;rsquo;ve become aware of potential shortages in decking screws. It&amp;rsquo;s a reminder to always stay one step ahead and ensure we have an adequate supply of essential materials. Playing to his strengths, Erny estimated the remaining wood we have for the battens, internal wall, and loft sections. Luckily, it seems like we have just enough to complete these crucial elements without any delays or the need to purchase additional materials.
Amidst the hard work, we&amp;rsquo;ve also made time for celebrations and cherished moments. Zy travelled all the way from Alice Springs on her birthday weekend to lend a hand with sanding and spend time with our chickens (pesky Agatha, Bertha and Clementine). Happy belated birthday, Zy!
Putting our friends to work
Happy Birthday Zy!
What&amp;rsquo;s next? As we venture into new territory, we&amp;rsquo;re currently strategising on how to install our windows. It&amp;rsquo;s a significant milestone that will transform our tiny house into a cosy and light-filled space. We&amp;rsquo;re researching different techniques, seeking advice from everywhere we can get it (thank you very much AGWA), and drawing on our own creativity to ensure the windows are installed in some shape and form. That&amp;rsquo;s it for now - June has been a month of challenges, inspiration, and progress. We appreciate everyone&amp;rsquo;s continued support and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to share more updates soon.
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny</description><category>build_update</category><category>cladding</category><category>sanding</category><category>shopping</category><category>tiny_house</category></item><item><title>May Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-may-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-may-build-update/</guid><description>An May build update Wrapping the tiny house like a present 🎁🎁🎁
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Hello, hello! As May rolls on, the days are getting shorter, and our productivity has slowed down. Not to make this blog become a Let's complain about the weather blog, but with the weather changing, we&amp;rsquo;ve had to battle with the elements to get any work done. Sunny weekdays are always followed by rainy weekends, leaving us only a few good hours to work on our project. To find a silver lining, we have become masters of water management though - devising a very high tech system of tarps and buckets to ensure minimal pooling.
We love puddles
Our focus has been on rushing to get the roof rafters up, but things are taking longer than anticipated. We&amp;rsquo;ve had to make a few tweaks and adjustments as we go, ensuring that everything is perfect. One of our biggest challenges has been installing noggins to the roof. It&amp;rsquo;s a fiddly job, requiring precision and patience due to using second-hand materials. We are installing three noggins between each rafter space, and it is looking good! Speaking of noggins - we&amp;rsquo;ve also installed our wall noggins to increase the structural integrity of the tiny house. This was unexpected and was partly due to the fact that Lys learnt how to use another tool - the circular saw. Honestly, it is not her favourite - it is ungainly and cumbersome to use with Lys&amp;rsquo; tiny little hands struggling to hold the circular saw steady. It is also dreadfully fussy and constantly complains (via not cutting properly, blade binding and making concerning noisy) and does not even cut accurately (totally not the fault of the user). But, because of Lys&amp;rsquo; ability to get over her hatred of the circular saw Erny was able to focus on installing those noggins.
The roof rafter structure
The roof noggins are up and installed
We also installed the eaves on the far ends of the house. This was particularly thrilling, being 3 meters in the air carrying a very heavy eave, but also because the house is starting to look like a real house. Huge thanks to Lys&amp;rsquo; brother and father for being MVPs holding ladders and being extra hands - could not have finished this job up in May without them! Erny also powered through and ripped through a bunch of roof battens in preparation for our roof install - it feels like things are really coming together.
However, it would not be a build update with a slight mishap. While Lys was working on the ladder she dropped a hammer - which smashed straight through the plywood subfloor. It was bound to happen at one point, but it was incredibly frustrating. We have patched the hole (nothing that glue and plywood cannot fix) but it is still a downer.
We were then blessed with a stretch of sunny weather, so we made the decision to wrap the house. Inspired by a YouTuber and tiny house builder named Two Hands and a Tiny House, we opted to use Fletcher Foam Cell Shed Liner for our house wrap. This product is 5 millimetres thick, featuring a lime green foam core and an anti-glare covering (though the debate about the colour of the anti-glare covering is still ongoing between Lys, Bel, and Erny). Unlike other house wrap it is quite heavy and holds its structure. It took immense effort, three ladders, and unwavering determination to wrap the entire house. When you&amp;rsquo;re perched on a ladder 4 meters high holding a roll of foam, the world takes on a different perspective, and you appreciate the magnitude of your project.
Measuring the house wrap
The house wrap is very reflective
The incredible Bel
Bel stopped by on Saturday to lend an extra pair of hands with impeccable timing. Together we balanced precariously on ladders and clambered around tiny house noggins to tap in the clout nails and wrangle the foam wrap, making the process smoother and more efficient. By the end of Saturday (most likely due to Erny&amp;rsquo;s determination) we had finished two layers so sisalation! What a feat. Then, Silvia joined us on Sunday, and lent us her engineering wisdom to help us figure out the most efficient way to wrap the eaves and the roof with the remaining house wrap. After a bit of mathematics and calculations (on Erny&amp;rsquo;s part) later, together with Lys&amp;rsquo; family (father, mother and brother are working overtime on this project), we installed the final three pieces of sisalation over the roof as the afternoon turned to dusk.
Strategising with Silvia
In a slight segue, Lys also took the opportunity to learn how to use the sled on the table saw to make roof spacers! It was a new skill to master, but with practice and Silvia&amp;rsquo;s supervision, she managed to create precise and uniform spacers that will ensure proper ventilation and airflow under the roof. We haven&amp;rsquo;t used them yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s all about those little details that make a big difference in the long run.
However, the true test for our house wrap will come next week when rain is in the forecast. We&amp;rsquo;re curious to see how the material holds up against wind and water. Two Hands and a Tiny House says it held up, but time will tell. As a precaution, Lys has been busy taping up the bottom of the trailer with Fletcher Vapastop 883, a reinforced foil tape known for its exceptional strength, flexibility, and conformability. The aluminium tape provides an added layer of protection against moisture and helps seal any potential gaps. Lys isn&amp;rsquo;t 100% sure what the 883 stands for, but it&amp;rsquo;s getting the job done.
Taping the edges to prevent water coming through
Erny working on the eave
The first section of the tiny house wrapped
The house wrapped at night
What&amp;rsquo;s next? Cladding, a window install&amp;hellip;maybe progress on a metal roof - who knows? Overall, May has been a month of challenges, adjustments, and learning experiences. While our productivity has slowed down with the shorter days, but clearly that hasn&amp;rsquo;t stopped us as we&amp;rsquo;ve made progress on important tasks like installing noggins, adding eaves, and wrapping the house. Each step brings the tiny house (also known as cubby house by the neighbours) closer to a reality, and it feels pretty surreal.
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny</description><category>build_update</category><category>insulation</category><category>water</category><category>roof</category><category>tiny_house</category><category>two_hands_and_a_tiny_house</category></item><item><title>April Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-apr-build-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-apr-build-update/</guid><description>An April build update We got some walls up!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done A timeline of sorts What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What a hectic last few days! Erny and I took some time off to focus on the tiny house full-time over the Easter break. For us, the past week has been a rollercoaster ride of highs and lows, with the weather constantly threatening to rain on our parade. It has been a lesson in patience, and willingness to adapt and learning as we go. But we&amp;rsquo;ve soldiered on, and I&amp;rsquo;m proud to say that we&amp;rsquo;ve made some significant progress - we can&amp;rsquo;t wait to update you!
Below is a semi-detailed blow-by-blow breakdown of our tiny house blitz. But if you can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered - just look at the pictures! Video is coming soon but Lys needs to take a nap.
A timeline of sorts The break started out with a wet and dreary weekend forecast, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t let that dampen our spirits. We decided to make use of the time by working in the garage and cutting wall studs. We also cleaned up the trailer of the mouldy plywood and updated the tiny house model.
Updating the model
Cutting studs in the garage
This time last year we had planned to raise the walls over the Easter break, but then Lys caught COVID and there were huge storms up and down the east coast. Our tentative first steps in 2022 fell to the wayside and moulded over in wet conditions. In 2022 we realised we were not ready so we re-grouped for 2023 Easter! It might not have been glamorous work, but it was necessary, and it felt good to be moving forward from the ghosts of 2022.
Slightly behind schedule but still feeling optimistic - Monday was a surprise, as we woke up to no rain! Over the past 10 days, we&amp;rsquo;ve been looking hawkishly at the weather forecast every half hour or so - it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been the healthiest. Lys took advantage of the dry weather and re-applied the damp course onto the trailer. The damp course will act as a thermal bridge between the cold steel of the trailer and the plywood. We are hoping this will reduce condensation and mould underneath the house. We also set up our new (to us) second-hand 6x3 m gazebo over the trailer. This was a huge lifesaver as we could work under the gazebo, protected from the intermittent showers. The forecasted rain still held off and Lys pressed forward and constructed our subfloor while Erny continued cutting studs in the garage. Lys got some great practice with the impact driver, and it felt pretty surreal that we actually screwed pieces of wood together. Finally some tangible progress!
Constructing the subfloor
Tuesday was another day where we were at the mercy of the rain gods, but again, they were kind to us. Lys glued the plywood down to the subfloor, and Erny continued cutting the wood for the frame. We also cut our metal strap bracing in preparation for a wall raising. In normal construction, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do this but we wanted to front-load as many activities as possible to maximise the good stretches of weather. Lys learnt how to use a new tool - tin-snips - thanks to a handy youtube video.
Youtube really can teach you anything!
Wednesday was a bit of a stress-fest, as we discovered we needed an emergency bolt order from Queensland. Somehow we had forgotten that a section of the trailer steel was thinner (by 6 cm) than the other areas of the trailer - what a rookie mistake! It was a hectic half hour trying to work out what extra bolts were required (14cm and 16cm if you were curious) and making an express order with Bolt and Nut Australia. Mid-afternoon showers really slowed the great progress we had made over the last few days but managed to build our first wall! Lys made the first wall all by herself, mastering yet another tool - this time the impact driver. We are using square-headed stainless steel screws due to stainless steel&amp;rsquo;s resistance to corrosion and strength - but my goodness are they easy to strip. We must have used over 500 screws on this project so far and Lys has ruined over 15 screw heads😞.
She has been binge listening to a cyber security history-based podcast called Malicious Life. It has been the perfect replacement for her true crime addiction and makes mundane tasks fly by. The stress continued into the evening with another emergency Bunnings run with Lys&amp;rsquo; brother to find nails. It turns out that we needed more special fastener connector nails and these special nails are different to the normal flat head or clout nails. It turns out that timber connector plate nails are designed and manufactured from a single piece of metal. In comparison, the shaft and head of a regular clout are manufactured separately and then joined. Because of this, the head of a regular clout may pop off a lot easier which results in a lower holding capacity. This means - even though they look exactly the same fastener connector nails are far superior (and a tad more expensive). To make matters worse we could not find the correct fastener nails in the correct dimensions. Regardless we decided to press onwards - though things were feeling a fit dire (mild exaggeration).
Will Lys and Erny have enough connector nails?
In a rapid turn of events - on Thursday we finished framing our picture window wall and our tallest long wall! We were pleased with the progress, but the sporadic rain forced us to quickly rainproof our materials with tarps. Scared from the memories of the 2022 rains, Erny had this brilliant idea to make a makeshift shower screen with an old tarp to protect the trailer and our newly created walls. The good fortune continued with our bolt order coming in! Clearly, purchasing express shipping was worth every penny and now we had all the bolts we needed to bolt the subfloor and the walls to the trailer.
Walls in progress
The next day was one of the most fun - our friends came around to lend a hand! We were grateful for the help of Troy, Silvia, and Jason as we framed the last wall and started drilling subfloor holes. This last wall was by far our most complex and Troy was an absolute wizard with the tape measure and Silvia took charge of cutting the last headers for our walls. Jason literally crushed putting our wall together and had sage advice when it came to the most efficient way to drill our subfloor.
We also made a few booboos here. It turns out the the headers in the model were the incorrect size which meant our loft windows were not perfectly aligned. Additionally Erny cut a king stud too short even though we had always measured twice before we cut. On top of this - we discovered that because of the bottom and top plates of the short walls being 45mm thick and the bottom and top plates of the long walls being 35mm our whole plan was just a little bit out of whack. How frustrating!
But alas we pressed on and together, Silvia and Jason made light work drilling through the subfloor and using a very blunt spade bit to make the insets for the bolt heads. Making things with friends was a rewarding experience, and building a big thing is made better with banter, laughs and collective problem-solving. Big thanks to Jason and Silvia for bringing over their gear and (perhaps more importantly ) their pizza oven for a delicious dinner! We also learned that even the best-laid plans, such as our Sketch-Up model, can differ from the reality of construction, and we had to make adjustments based on practical considerations. Delicious sausage rolls, courtesy of Troy&amp;rsquo;s partner Deborah, were a welcomed treat after a productive day.
Friends lending a helping hand
Silvia on the circular saw
There is always time for lunch 🥪
Drilling holes
Jason on the pizza oven
We had a life break on Saturday but Sunday was a day of significant progress as Erny made the first full hole through the trailer, marking a significant milestone. We had made yet another stop to Bunnings to purchase an extra long drill bit to give us the best chance of drilling through over 12 cm of wood and steel. It was a great decision but it was very slow going - a solid 9 minutes per hole at top drill speed! Everyone lent a hand - drilling a hole into through the trailer steel. A huge shout out to Lys&amp;rsquo; dad who put in some serious elbow grease drilling through the steel.
We also decided to strap and square the walls while they were on the ground instead of when they were vertical on the trailer. This way is easier for just the two of us and allowed us to maximise all the hands we had. Remember those fastener connector nails that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t find earlier? Well, soon we would be finding out if a little 250-gram box would successfully strap 4 walls of a tiny house&amp;hellip; Somehow, we squared and strapped most of our walls, relying on tensioners to keep them square and rearranged our timeline to increase our chances of getting the walls up. Bel came to lend a hand in the afternoon, and her assistance with drilling holes helped us work faster and prepare for the wall raising on Monday. Lys brother&amp;rsquo;s chickens kept her good company pottering about the trailer while Bel drilled. It may have been because Bel brought the best snacks (nothing like some Kettles chips). You could feel the toll of the week set in a little as we were getting a little frustrated as progress was slower than anticipated.
Bel on the tiny stool drilling through the metal
By the time Monday rolled around again we were determined to have these walls raised, despite the chilly Autumn weather. We started the day by watching Laura Kamp for inspiration as we worked. The day did not start off well - Lys&amp;rsquo; wrist felt so sore she couldn&amp;rsquo;t hold a drill or an impact driver. We felt like we were slowing down big time and we still needed to finish drilling and bolting the subfloor down. Luckily help was on the way with our good friends Dan and Michael. Dan - also known as drill man came to our aid and absolutely obliterated (in a good way) our holes through the trailer. Forget 9 minutes per hole - Dan was finished in 5! Michael also finished hammering in the metal strapping to our final wall - and as a bonus - added stud ties to each stud. That little box of nails covered all four walls with strapping with a few nails to spare😛
With holes now drilled, we then proceeded to bolt our subfloor down. We had a scare with bolts and fasteners going missing but it turned out that they were hiding, being misplaced in a screw box. Then, with the the help of drill man Dan, we installed the perimeter floorboards onto the subfloor. We had actually originally decided to fasten the entire flooring down and insulating before we raised the walls however, to save time, we instead just put in the floorboards around the perimeter of the trailer to support the framing. It was not ideal and we will probably encounter some difficulties down the track but we really wanted to maximise the time we had working on the house.
Lys under the trailer bolting screws
Bolts are in
Adding the perimeter floorboards to the subfloor
It really felt like it was all coming together! We took a break to enjoy a delicious lunch of truffle brie cheese and late-season tomatoes, a little indulgence to fuel our bodies for the hard work ahead. Then with many hands and lots of positivity, after lunch, we raised the walls! It seriously took a small village. We lifted, coordinated and maneuvered these heavy walls into position. Using extra bracing, we secured our walls to the subfloor and then ensured that everything was as square and plumb as possible. It was overwhelming to see the whole wall frame come to life, and it still felt surreal. Honestly - the walls are so much taller than we expected&amp;hellip;and it didn&amp;rsquo;t have a roof yet. Huge thanks to Dan and Michael for staying that little bit longer to put these walls up - we could not have done it without you both!
Michael strapping the walls
Dan and Lys&amp;rsquo; dad chatting about drill bits
Completed walls
The excitement was not over, however - Erny and Lys were also mindful of an upcoming storm on Thursday that could potentially cause issues with wood swelling and mould. Water makes wood swell and that causes issues when dealing with framing if it shrinks back to normal size. There&amp;rsquo;s a fancy word for this actually - hygroscopy! High levels of lumber moisture content may also result in mould - and we can&amp;rsquo;t have that happen! Lys is frantically googling how to keep worksites as dry as possible and Erny is strategizing how we can put the roof on as quickly as possible.
On the last day of our Tiny House blitz, Erny took on the task of working on the roof alone with Lys being back at work. He attached the frame securely to the trailer and installed Simpson hurricane ties, which proved to be a challenging task at height. High up on the ladder he methodically worked his way around each stud, 3 meters in the air. Then he with Lys&amp;rsquo; mum, sanded into our rafters that we had made the month before. Later in the day, Lys joined after work, and together with the help of Lys&amp;rsquo; parents, we managed to get seven out of eleven roof rafters up, racing against time and impending Thursday rain. To protect the frame from said upcoming rain, we used a large gazebo tarp as a makeshift roof. It is not perfect, but it served its purpose and hopefully will keep our progress safe from the elements - watch this space!
Roof rafters are half on
Reflecting on the past break, it&amp;rsquo;s been a whirlwind of activity. We&amp;rsquo;ve had our fair share of slip-ups and mistakes - like our emergency bolt purchase and cutting studs too short, but we&amp;rsquo;ve also learned a lot along the way. It&amp;rsquo;s been gratifying to see all of our weeks and months of prep come to fruition, and it feels like it&amp;rsquo;s all coming together. We&amp;rsquo;ve also learned the importance of working with others and how to make use of their strengths at short notice. As a duo, it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes hard to delegate and make use of multiple people, but we&amp;rsquo;ve found that when we work with friends, it&amp;rsquo;s much more enjoyable and productive. Sometimes we felt like we were rushing so we would not waste others&amp;rsquo; time but we definitely learnt to slow down and trust the process by the third day of working with friends. A huge thank you to our family who were so supportive and accommodating - thank you for keeping us fed, making sure we slept, being always on stand by and ready to lend a hand. To Silvia and Jason whose extra drills were an absolute lifesaver and Troy who provided delicious sausage rolls and buckets of positivity. A huge thank you to Bel for bringing the best snacks. Finally, mega claps to Dan and Michael who were absolute troupers, rolling their sleeves up to lift some heavy Douglas fir walls, helping us get close to making this tiny house a reality.
Looking back on the schedule, we did not manage to achieve everything we had hoped for. Due to rain and setbacks, we ended up 2 days behind schedule and we have not dried in our house which means that we are at the mercy of the elements. We suppose that, like most things, construction and DIY take longer than we expect. However, we did not expect to come this far and seeing walls up is such a huge milestone - something truly to feel proud of😄.
Finally, we&amp;rsquo;ve discovered the joys of using screws! They&amp;rsquo;re like a CTRL-Z button, allowing us to undo our errors and easily reuse them.
Frame is up!
What&amp;rsquo;s next? Obviously we want to get to dry-in but Erny is off to Bendigo and Lys is going to have a long, long nap 😴
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny</description><category>build_update</category><category>frame</category><category>door</category><category>roof</category><category>subfloor</category><category>tiny_house</category></item><item><title>March Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/mar-2023-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/mar-2023-build-update/</guid><description>A March build update A door, some floor progress and general reflections.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Hello from The Miette HQ! The last half of February and March has been a busy and productive month for Erny and Lys, and thanks to an unseasonably dry month on the coast we have made some great progress on the tiny.
We kicked off the month by refurbishing our 40-year-old door. We had been looking for a narrow external french door for a while and rescued this gem from a renovation down south. The door had quite a bit of - let us say character, but the glass was intact, the wood in great condition and the correct dimensions! We got to work sanding down the varnish and stain and this time, compared to the windows it was an absolute breeze.
Pre-sanded door
Sanded door
In fact, the whole door refurbishment project was finished in about three days - so much shorter than building our own windows 😂 Erny, being the perfectionist he is, decided to route and chisel out the area of the gouge and make a little inset to fill it back up. We think it was from a dog or small animal scratching at the wall when it was hung in a previous home. Lys actually didn&amp;rsquo;t mind the gouge, but it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the differences in our personalities come out during these types of projects. Lys tends to prioritise efficiency and sticking to a schedule, while Erny is all about quality and is not done until it&amp;rsquo;s done to the very best of his ability, even if it takes twice as long.
Fitting the inset to fix the door gouge
Completed inset
Stained inset in our door
Even though this door project was super speedy, we are however a little stuck on the lock mechanism though - it seems that since this door is a little thinner than modern doors and we will have to make a few tweaks to its dimensions for it to fit a modern lock system. Considering that we could go lockless for a little while (at least until after a wall raising), we decided to put that problem on the back burner to focus on more solvable problems.
Finished refurbished doors - Lys swears they look different from when we first acquired them
In addition to the door, we also started to put together our rafter pieces using Fred&amp;rsquo;s tiny house rafter sandwich technique. This is a recommended tiny house rafter design where we sandwich plywood around the rafters and bolt it all together instead of attaching to a ridge beam. The idea here is to reduce weight while retaining a solid roof structure. We ran into a bit of a snag when we discovered that the model that we cut our rafters to was actually 10 mm short. This meant that all of our roof rafters were a little too short, and we needed to change the angle of the pieces slightly shallower to fit the to real house width.
Highlights Despite these setbacks, there have been some really nice moments in March. It has been nice working with the whole family in the garden, cracking out some tools that Lys&amp;rsquo; parents have not touched in years (like a set of extra large drill bits) and problem-solving small hiccups together. There have also been a few late nights working out last-minute logistics - from wanting our bathroom and kitchen floors to be at the same height makes our bathroom floor very complicated to what is the most efficient permutation of our floorboards for minimum waste - but we seem to be getting there. Lys&amp;rsquo; Dad jokes that we are slowly becoming Australia&amp;rsquo;s smallest Bunnings with the variety of drill bits, screws and nails that we are collecting.
Erny&amp;rsquo;s extremely scientific plan
We also made great headway on the subfloor. After re-purchasing plywood (our previous purchase became mouldy last year, but that is a story for another time), Lys got these new sheets primed and painted the plywood to get it ready for construction. Meanwhile, Erny has been busy cutting down subfloor joists to size and creating a detailed map of exactly where we are going to put our black butt floorboards down.
Priming the floor joists and plywood
Oh and how could we forget - we added another tool to our growing tool family! Erny purchased a Makita vacuum cleaner. At first glance it seems to add no direct value to the house, but it is an absolute game changer cleaning up offending wood shavings from the table and floor - our backs are super appreciative.
In summary, most of February and March has been focused on front-loading small jobs in preparation for our week of leave in April. The idea is to prepare as much as possible to maximise our week off. Honestly, it feels a bit like déjà vu - last year we tried to raise the walls and set the foundation, but unfortunately, Lys caught COVID around this time. We&amp;rsquo;re keeping our fingers crossed that she won&amp;rsquo;t get sick again and that we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to make more progress on the house during our upcoming break - Lys is once again checking the weather every 30 minutes.
Will it rain in April?
What&amp;rsquo;s next? Maybe Erny&amp;rsquo;s map of the floorboard efficiency comes to fruition?
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny
Grain is so nice in the douglas fir of our joists</description><category>build_update</category><category>door</category><category>roof</category><category>subfloor</category><category>tiny_house</category></item><item><title>How To Build a Window</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/how-to-build-a-window/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/how-to-build-a-window/</guid><description>Just a short update - Lys put together a little montage of our window building journey (over 8 months in the making) and we have started tackling the doors! Will update our door journey in the next post but for now enjoy the video!
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny</description><category>windows</category><category>video</category><category>canberra</category><category>tiny_house</category></item><item><title>January Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/jan-2023-build-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/jan-2023-build-update/</guid><description>A January build update We get glass in window frames.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done In December last year Lys&amp;rsquo; parents gently highlighted that they want their garage back. So, with a deadline of September 30th and some wonderful sunshine we decided to nail these windows down. Honestly, we try write these blogs once a month but sometimes its difficult to encapsulate every trial and tribulation when you cannot even begin to remember them all. Over December and January we worked on the windows over the Christmas break and over 4 weekends, with each day throwing up a new challenge.
A big moment though was nailing the glass into the finished frames. Erny hired an air compressor and a brad nail gun from our local tool library (more on this later) and we spent a good hour practicing how to effectively piece a nail into blackbutt, which consistently reminded us that it is a heavy wood that is tough to pierce through. You get a small jump scare whenever the nail goes into the wood and it is incredibly loud.
Measuring the beading to fit the bathroom window
Once Erny got the hang of it all we raced through attaching the beading and were (surprisingly) finished in no time. Nailing the beading in felt like this project is gaining a little bit of momentum, that it is actually doable, and that if we can build these we have a higher likelihood of tackling the rest of the house.
Back to the tool library - think of this as a place where people can share tools that they may only need on a once off (or very infrequent basis). Lys discovered this community a year ago when she was determining how we were going to source our tools. Having no need or space for an air compressor and nail gun on a daily basis, we thought it would be a great option to hire these larger tools out. They even provided a bunch of spare brad nails, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to buy any ourselves! Our local one is the Inner West Tool Library but you can also find others up and down the east coast.
Inner West Tool Library
The library has pretty much everything that you need
Another huge moment was screwing in the hinges to attach the inner and outer frame of our awning windows. These hinges have been the most finicky and needed quite a bit of coaxing. With the way the hinges open, the top edge of the inner window frame needs to be routed so that the edge doesn&amp;rsquo;t catch on the inner frame. With great care we screwed the them in and tadaaaaa - they look amazing! We now just need to attach the latches to ensure that the internal window can remain snuggle-y closed and locked and then these are ready to be installed into some walls. The stain does not look too bad too! Finally having a full awning indow that we can open and close is unbelievably satisfying - huge kudos to Erny and his unwavering attention to detail.
Look at those hinges
Highlights Lys worked up the courage to use the table saw by herself for the first time! Maybe Erny now has the confidence to let her use it unsupervised? We&amp;rsquo;ll find out soon enough&amp;hellip;
There is something oddly satisfying when you apply weather proofing foam to seal window frames. This foam goes in between the opening glass and the frame - it is squishy and has great bounce back and sticks to almost anything and is great to apply. Lys had a lot of fun applying this during her lunch breaks.
Another great memory was us deciding to &amp;ldquo;risk it for the biscuit&amp;rdquo; and take our huge picture window outside to fit the glass, weather seal and bead with a Summer storm on the horizon. Even though we did get a few drops on our precious window we managed to finish the job before the light ran out and the storm came in!
Racing against the rain and daylight to finish our picture window
Other than that&amp;hellip;.the window frames have glass in them!
Challenges There seems to be a big storm on the way across out state so timeline looks to be a little impacted.
What&amp;rsquo;s next? looking forward to some doors and floors (but realistically more window work - Erny&amp;rsquo;s a perfectionist) 🚪
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny</description><category>build_update</category><category>windows</category><category>tiny_house</category></item><item><title>November December Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/nov-dec-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/nov-dec-2022-build-update/</guid><description>An November December build update Window making continues with a side of weddings, berry farms, and other sundry end of year activities.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done So while writing this blog post, Lys discovers there&amp;rsquo;s a frisbee emoji 🥏 also known as the flying disc emoji - how random! Tiny house wise though - our journey continues working on our windows.
In November we spent most of our weekends sanding the burn marks off the blackbutt panels to get them ready for piecing. Having spent over 50 hours sanding over the course of 2 months using the orbital sander has really lost its shine, in fact the activity is nothing short of mundane. To combat sanding fatigue Erny has developed a strategy of listening to podcasts with earbuds under our earmuffs to while the time away.
Lys&amp;rsquo; brother helped out sanding down the huge picture window (big thanks!). November also saw us putting together the bathroom window (smallest) as a test run. This proved difficult as the pieces had bowed slightly and were not really sitting square. Erny decided that we needed to re-sand these pieces so they became more-square to give us the best hope of flush corners. This set us back a weekend as we worked overtime to re-sand the pieces.
Sanding sanding and more&amp;hellip;sanding
With the parts of the frame now square we had the arduous task of lining everything up to drill our pilot holes. With a contraption of too many clamps we raced against the sun to screw our window frames together which ended up with&amp;hellip; a fail. A piece or clamp must have shifted in the process and when Erny screwed the pieces together we could tell that our window would not fit our glass. So, over the week Lys puttied up the holes with sawdust, glue and putty for another crack at it. This time we started earlier and took our time. This ended with a beautifully square(ish) window frame!
A successful frame
With that small win we continued with the loft and kitchen windows. These also proved to be challenging as these three frames open. And it was here, design wise, we hit a little snag - we did not account for the hinges in our design. Our previous design did not account for hinge movement and so part of the hinges will be exposed to the elements. So back to the drawing board we went to see how we could integrate those hinges into our windows in a weather tight manner. Luckily Erny found this video, which is not only Australian but it details where and how one should install hinges on casement (and then by extension awning) windows.
Lys also happened to purchase a secondhand router earlier on in the year which came in handy. Having learnt our lesson from previously failures we had the foresight to run a prototype to test if our in-layed hinge strategy would work as we expected - and it did! We then routed the edges off our frames to inlay the hinges into our frames. Success!
Prototype
Ensuring the hinges are measured correctly
The 2nd hand router doing its good work
But it would not be a build update with another hiccup. We test drove the Osmo - UV Protection Oil on some spare blackbutt. It is lovely and pulls the colour of the wood out so well. It does however make the putty quite orange, and so Lys decided we needed to stain the wood to blend the putty into the blackbutt. We settled on Sikkens Cetol BLX-Pro Teak Timber Stain which was the lightest stain Bunnings offered that would hide the orange tone. After trialing it out on our bathroom window, Lys was not convinced that it camouflaged the putty orange. Mildly distraught, Lys mulled over if we should continue down the staining path. Ultimately we decided - yes - it would be a good idea to stain the wood as an undercoat.
Test piece highlighting the overly orange putty
Staining the pieces to teak perfection
From there we have been full steam ahead with the rest of our windows! Our big picture window frame has been completed as well as the internal window frames of all our opening windows. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too long before all of them have finished by the end of January&amp;hellip; (being hopeful here).
Our final December hurdle was a extremely scary glass fitting for our picture window. Measuring in at 1.2m x 1.5m and with a glass pane that is over 20kgs, we tentatively test fit our glass into the frame. Clearly our 2mm leeway must have been eaten up by a twist or a slight bend because the last glass fitting was tight. We will probably need to sand out the cavity in the new year.
Highlights Lys doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to jinks it but the weather has actually been really good these last few months! Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping for a productive 2023 🤞
Challenges Not so much of a challenge but we&amp;rsquo;re trying to enjoy life (and the good weather while we build). Congrats to Jo and Mandi :)
What&amp;rsquo;s next? More windows and maybe some walls? But also, have a safe and snazzy festive season and see you in 2023 ⭐
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny
Oiling windows</description><category>build_update</category><category>windows</category><category>tiny_house</category></item><item><title>Oct Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/oct-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/oct-2022-build-update/</guid><description>An October build update We got solar! ☀️ ☀️ ☀️
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done One of our neighbours decided to demolish their house without removing their 10 year old solar system (it was not cost effective for them to re-install). Luckily for us they said that if we could take it down we could have it! Erny clambered onto the roof on a balmy Sunday day to bring the panels down.
On the shopping front we spent hours online trawling for a dealer that would sell us heavy-duty fiction awning hinges for our loft and kitchen windows. For context, we will have three awning windows in the house that open outwards from the window sill1.
An example of an awning window
A friction hinge allows the opening part of the window to stay open or ajar for long periods of time2. This is handy if you want to open the window for airflow or escape from a fire (priorities aye?). Frictionless hinges would have the opening portion of the window fall back into its closed position quickly.
But because awning windows are currently not in fashion it was really hard to find the a vendor, and worse still - because our double glass is heavy it was virtually impossible to find options that could take the weight of the glass. We ended up going with a commercial style which is a little less than aesthetic but very sturdy.
We also spend way too long deciding what sort of latches we were going to use to close the windows shut and most importantly - what colour they should be. It turns out that with awning windows one can only use one type of latch. These are called wedge fasteners and Lys couldn&amp;rsquo;t - for the life of her - find a good example of how they should be installed. Luckily the lovely team at Restoration Online were so helpful and stepped Lys through all things fasteners. We opted for polished brass across all fixtures, because it looks pretty and is quite popular meaning we may be able to snag some second hand deals if some unfortunate renovator accidentally purchases the incorrect size/amount.
If you ever wanted to know how wedge fasteners work
As a side note - if you ever are in the market for fixtures (think door handles, window fixings, locks or gate hooks) there seems to be only one player in the Australian market and that is TradCo (unless you go with something particularly boutique). We only say this because all online offerings look the same. Heck - some even call the TradCo products fancy names but use the same stock photos as the TradCo online PDF pamphlet3. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing but it is difficult as a consumer to compare and contrast if everything is exactly the same.
We also played around with the second-hand router that Lys found off facebook marketplace for a steal.
Highlights Getting the solar panels was such a huge highlight. Erny says that compared to the current market these solar panels would be about 60% as efficient but a new suite of panels (+ installation) would be approximately $4000 so it seems unfair to compare. We also did not expect to get solar so soon - if at all - so it was a nice win. ☀️ Side note: made a short vid (with gentle encouragement from a friendly social media savvy human - looking at you Lydia! &amp;#x1f604;)
Challenges We snapped a few more drill bits and need to purchase an 18v drill. Currently we have a 12v and a 9v but drilling pilot holes through the blackbutt is proving difficult. We&amp;rsquo;re also filling up a lot of our mistakes so another order of wood filler may be required.
What&amp;rsquo;s next? Lys is desperate to finish a window. Just one would be nice&amp;hellip;
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny
Window sketch up credits&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
If for some reason you want to learn about torque on friction hinges: go here&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
Check out pretty door handles in the TradCo pamphlet&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description><category>solar</category><category>build_update</category><category>video</category><category>windows</category><category>tiny_house</category></item><item><title>August September 2022 Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 13:54:47 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</guid><description>An August September build update Hello Spring! Working almost every weekend, these last two months we&amp;rsquo;ve actually got a proper build update &amp;#x1f604;.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done We went through our stash of 90x45mm lengths and picked out roof rafters. These have been measured down to a 20 degree angle and some have been cut to size! We&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this in the garage when there has been a rain shower break and it has worked quite well. Erny created a little jig to speed up the process and it has been great get that out of the way.
Working in the garage cutting window rafters
Then we spent 3 whole days stripping the faces of our cedar cladding boards. Originally, we were going to use paint stripper and scrape the old paint off but we found that method too slow. By shearing the face off the boards we can get to the beautiful grain quickly, but it does substantially decrease the thickness down from 19mm to 15mm, which is just enough to continue using the pieces as cladding. We still need to cut out to extend the tongue and grooves of each piece (there are about 70 3m pieces to fix up) but that&amp;rsquo;s a future problem. It is truly a labour of love refurbishing this cladding but we think it will be worth it! Western Red Cedar is often $30 - $40 per lineal meter as it is not grown in Australian plantations and so we are very lucky to have found some at no cost on the secondary market (good work Erny!).
Stripping western red cedar cladding
We&amp;rsquo;ve finally tweaked and re-tweaked our design for our custom windows. We are kind of following a process similar to Project Kamp - they made a comprehensive video about their window journey which you can watch below.
Like Project Kamp, we are also using double glazed windows (see our post on our recent-ish trip to Canberra) but we are using Blackbutt frames. We also purchased EPDM414 self adhesive window tape from Clark Rubber to keep our windows water and air tight. Clark Rubber is this rubber and pool store in Australia that has a bright yellow platypus as its logo - Honestly Lys had never been to Clark Rubber before and it was just a random experience. Who knew that there were so many rubber products available to the retail market?
Then our much awaited week of leave came around! We spent most of our week off machining these window frames down to size and cutting channels and beading. Honestly this was pretty slow going - measuring, cutting, re-measuring our mistakes but we are definitely closer to putting our glass into the frames.
Cutting window pieces to size
Finished window pieces
Feature Window (our biggest window) Pieces
Finally, our finishing oil and putty came in the mail and Lys is excited to use some new products. We are going to protect our blackbutt frames with an product from Osmo - UV Protection Oil1. This stuff is literally the good oil - being easy to prepare, easy to apply and easy to maintain. It is also made of natural oils (sunflower oil, soya oil, thistle oil and linseed oil) and has lower amounts of volatile chemicals.
The only down side to this product is that we had to ship it from Queensland! It seems that there are no retailers in our state who stock this product at an affordable price&amp;hellip;
Highlights We got another extension cord! This may not sound like much but we have been working on one singular powerpoint. Having another extension cord means that we can use (wait for it&amp;hellip;) a whopping two power tools at the same time. It&amp;rsquo;s the little things that bring joy you know?
Challenges Our week off came with a few challenges! The few days prior Lys religiously checked the weather forecast every hour on the hour to see what our prospects were for full days of work. Luckily the forecast was more conservative than usual and we managed to get over 8 hours of work in per day.
We also had a few issues with our very faithful Makita table saw and tool set. We were making some cross cuts on the table saw and discovered that NOTHING was square. It turns out that the set square the we had been using was out by 1mm. This isn&amp;rsquo;t an issue when we are working on larger longer pieces (e.g cladding) but is a positive nightmare when it comes to woodworking that requires more finesse (cough the windows). To remediate, we set off for an emergency (and actually square) set square which made our lives a whole lot easier (and more accurate). We also discovered the benefits - and it sounds a little silly - to cleaning the table saw blade. We were experiencing inconvenient friction burn marks on our blackbutt wood and our friend Silvia suggested that it may be time for a new blade or a quick clean. Taking pause to maintain our tools reduced the friction burn marks and allowed us to eek a few more cuts out of the old blade.
Got somewhat distracted by all the Makita products
What&amp;rsquo;s next? Australia&amp;rsquo;s Bureau of Meteorology (BOM) has officially confirmed that we are heading into yet another La Niña, our 3rd consecutive wet Summer so honestly not feeling very hopeful. But slow progress is still progress so that is something.
I am not crying about the rain are crying about the rain
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny
Read the technical specs of Osmo here&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description><category>build_update</category><category>tiny_house</category><category>windows</category><category>cladding</category><category>cedar</category></item><item><title>Operation Find a Roof</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/operation-find-a-roof/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 19:26:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/operation-find-a-roof/</guid><description>Operation Find a Roof As Lys sits down to write this she can officially say that we have sourced all of our roof components! It is a mixture of second hand material and some first-hand non-negotiable(s) but it&amp;rsquo;s great to finally have all the bits and bobs.
Table Of Contents The Design The Material Gutters Sundry Items The Design We chose to have a slightly off centred gable roof for our tiny house. Technically this is known as a saltbox pitch style but we have not found that term used commonly in Australia. We wanted to keep the traditional house style compared to some of the more modern tiny house options. The style is also quite useful for maximising solar panels on a small space and this will be helpful if we decide to go off-grid. It is also simple to construct as there are minimal valleys or curves which makes it great for novice builders also known as cough us.
Our roof design
We are going to have a roof pitch of 20 degrees (which is standard for most houses and easier to find second hand materials for) even though we could have as little as a 5 degree roof pitch for a gable roof. Most tiny houses choose a shed style or flat roof which is technically more space economical as one can get more internal head height but we really liked the more traditional aesthetic. There is just something so comfortable and cosy about a gable roof.
Gable, Saltbox, Flat and Shed roof styles are all common tiny house options
The Material Metal was our go to choice for a roof - it&amp;rsquo;s light, relatively affordable and easy to come by on the second hand market. Often larger jobs will order 10% extra as leeway and sell the remainder. We actually found our Colorbond from a lovely family fixing a shed, a elderly couple redoing a carport and a renovation on the Central Coast.
On our way up from the Central Coast we had this brilliant idea to cut the Colorbond panelling with tin snips to fit the sheets into the van. It turns out that it is incredibly difficult to cut corrugated iron with tin snips (think of these like scissors for metal) over long distances and most people just use a circular saw or angle grinder. Luckily we had a rope that Erny was given from another pick up and we bundled 6m pieces of Colorbond into the back of the van and tied the boot closed for a 1.5hr drive home. Note to self - always bring a circular saw!
But what about the colour?
Lys absolutely adores a dark coloured and black roof. It is the current tiny house trend at the moment and looks very sleek, blending into the the environment if it is particularly verdant. The building industry also loves a good dark roof as well1.
That being said - the colour is not the ideal colour in sunny Australia, or anywhere warm in this changing climate2. Long story short - dark coloured surfaces absorb more heat energy than lighter colours. In a roofing context this heats the roof cavity of your home and - unless you have great insulation - heats the interior of your home. On a broader scale, with urban sprawl suburbs can fall victim to the Urban Heat Island3 effect - where urban centers are significantly warmer than rural areas due to having less trees and more dark surfaces.
At one point in time Australian states were looking to ban dark coloured roofs on new developments.
Having said this - a tiny house roof is very small so in the grand scheme of things it probably won&amp;rsquo;t matter, but as Australia&amp;rsquo;s cities experience more urban sprawl it is more important than ever to make small steps to heat-proof abodes - and this means Lys must sacrifice her dark coloured roof.
So we are going with Surf Mist as our roof colour! Solar Absorptance (SA) is the proportion of the total incident solar radiation that is absorbed by the roofing material (the remainder is reflected) and a roof with a lower solar absorptance will absorb less heat than a roof with a higher solar absorptance. Theoretically, this should keep the roof space and building cooler on a hot day.
Surfmist has a SA of 0.32 - compared to Monument (an incredibly popular tiny house roof colour) which has a SA of 0.71. Obviously if we had our time again we&amp;rsquo;d love to use Whitehaven or Dover White (SA of 0.23) but it seems like it is not available for retail consumers, rather it is an architectural offering only.
Classic Colorbond Colours
Gutters We found the gutters in the Haberfield of all places. A heritage listed house had accidentally ordered the incorrect gutter type in the colour that we were looking for (Surfmist) and we pounced. We ended up getting them for free as well &amp;#x1f604; We actually ended up using the same rope to secure our gutters in the van - we suppose the real take away here is always bring a rope when picking up second hand construction items.
Taking off gutters
Sundry Items It was most difficult trying to find flashing, ridge caps and rivets second hand. We ended up purchasing on the first-hand market (and rust is a thing so we thought this would be the best approach). This posed another problem as most suppliers are not interested in servicing such a small job or they are a full service fit out (i.e. they provide the product and the installation service). Other vendors wouldn&amp;rsquo;t match the existing gutters that we had or were not based in our state - shipping costs are a killer! Additionally, with rising construction costs website prices were inflated from 5% - 20% on the personalized quote.
Luckily we found Jack from Roofit Online which had an online store (because as we know Millennials avoid talking on the phone like the plague) and 24/7 customer service. They specialise in Colorbond and locally manufacture. What they can&amp;rsquo;t make they source though their team based in NSW as well.They also take all types of jobs no matter how small which is great when building a tiny house. Jack was super patient and chucked a 5% discount - thanks Jack! We only have good things to say.
So here we are - one nerdy rant later about roof colours and we are a little bit closer to putting ours up!
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny
Find out why people like dark roofs with Renew&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
If you feel extra nerdy Lys found this paper on roof performance around the world a great read&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
Urban Heat Island Effect is a term used to describe the outer suburbs of major cities with minimal tree cover. Interesting articles from the Climate Council can be read here and from Adapt NSW here&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description><category>roofing</category><category>tiny_house</category></item><item><title>July 2022 Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/july-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 20:15:04 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/july-2022-build-update/</guid><description>A July build update What have we done? Absolutely nothing. Lys honestly thinks it&amp;rsquo;s been the wettest July that we&amp;rsquo;ve lived through in sunny Australia.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Erny jetted off to the US for a few weeks to play ultimate frisbee! Left to her own devices Lys did a few sundry things like source suppliers for our metal connectors. We&amp;rsquo;ve also added a few new features to the site - now you can add comments and now subscribe if you feel so inclined. Is Lys using this project to learn some coding skills on the side? Maybe&amp;hellip;👀
We&amp;rsquo;ve also got a new Resources Page up so hopefully if there&amp;rsquo;s anyone else out there who&amp;rsquo;s crazy enough to build their own shed/tiny house/trailer/van thing they&amp;rsquo;ll have an easier time of it than we did &amp;#x1f604;
Challenges 🌧️
What&amp;rsquo;s next? Fingers crossed this rain goes away so we can prep our walls for assembly in August! Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll end up finalising our roof&amp;hellip;who knows really. We&amp;rsquo;re going to take a week off in September to pull up the walls, roof and walls so no pressure!
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny</description><category>build_update</category><category>tiny_house</category><category>rain</category><category>tiny_house</category></item><item><title>A Quick Trip to Canberra</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/a-quick-trip-to-canberra/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 19:26:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/a-quick-trip-to-canberra/</guid><description>A quick trip to Canberra In January we sped down to Canberra to pick up some double glazed glass for our windows. We had been on the hunt for double glazed glass closer to home but it seems that Canberra - having cold winters - has great reclaimed glass options.
Table Of Contents Introducing Handyman Trading Post A side step antiquing So what&amp;rsquo;d you get? But why use double glazing?
Weight is a huge issue in tiny house construction (we need to keep the building under 4.5 tonnes) and double glazed glass is notoriously heavy. This is fine for a traditional build but for tiny house construction builders often choose to install single paned glass. We chose double paned glass because firstly, Erny wanted this feature, but also because our windows will take a good percentage of our wall surface area. We&amp;rsquo;re also trying out a continuous band of insulation on top of insulation batting to reduce thermal bridging in light of Passive House design so it would be a pity to have insulated walls but have all our heat leak out of our windows. We&amp;rsquo;re also not planning on adding active heating mechanisms (e.g air-con) to the Miette if we have to so choosing double glazed windows seems like a good way to go for now.
Introducing Handyman Trading Post Handymans Trading Post specialises in used building materials and seems to be the only place that sells double glazed glass on the east coast. Erny found them on Facebook Marketplace and they were super friendly online. They recommended that we pop down in person to see their panes and even though they were in another state the trip was well worth it.
The Handyman Trading Post
Windows everywhere!
When we went in January, they had some great stock (which is what you get from over 41 years in business). They seem to have Australia&amp;rsquo;s collection cedar doors and window frames and some of the nicest stained glass windows too. You can find more about Handyman Trading Post here.
Canberra has the best stock
Note: they close at 1PM on Saturdays so if you are traveling from afar, factor this in! We arrived at 12:30 - just in time to pick up our glass.
A side step antiquing There&amp;rsquo;s also a cute antique store named Down Memory Lane which is just opposite so we spent some time there checking out the wares. The stock seems so much cheaper than up North and the furniture was in top quality. Definitely recommend a looksee.
Canberra has the best stock
So what&amp;rsquo;d you get? So after months of looking we have our double glazed glass for our custom windows!
Our picture window is a generous 1400 x 1100mm and will be our main feature. It&amp;rsquo;s currently residing in Lys&amp;rsquo; office covered by a towel. Our kitchen window pane is a little larger than we anticipated coming in at (470x1200mm). We&amp;rsquo;ll have to manipulate our walls to fit this window into our design. We lucked out with our bathroom window as there was only a small selection of frosted glass options but we came away with a thin long window which we should be able to put frosted film on.
Finally, we were super lucky to get two panes exactly the same dimensions for our loft windows (at 300x900mm)!
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny
Arrive early if you&amp;rsquo;re traveling far</description><category>canberra</category><category>windows</category><category>tiny_house</category></item><item><title>June 2022 Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/june-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 23:15:04 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/june-2022-build-update/</guid><description>A June build update Decided that we should do monthly build updates as we march towards the end of the year. We&amp;rsquo;re hoping to reach lock up by then (walls, floor and roof complete) and 31st December is our D-day.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Erny bought a second hand table saw for $400 a few months back and it&amp;rsquo;s been an absolute workhorse. With it we&amp;rsquo;ve milled our wood down to size (70x45mm) for our walls and have started cutting down the blackbutt for our window frames.
Working with a job site table (one that&amp;rsquo;s portable) saw has meant there have been a few tweaks that we&amp;rsquo;ve had to make. The first is that the vibrations and when one rips though a particularly long length of wood the fence is prone to shifting. Erny hacked a wood piece to clamp on to the table saw to minimise this.
Milling douglas fir to size
Another is that the vibrations move the table saw forward on the table that we&amp;rsquo;re using. Once again clamps come to our rescue as we decided to clamp down two pieces of wood to the end of the table. These act as a stopper to stop the table saw shifting.
Cutting blackbutt to size
Something else that we&amp;rsquo;ve noticed is how good douglas fir smells. Apparently it smells like citrus but it just smells really fragrant. And as a soft wood it&amp;rsquo;s super light! Douglas fir is considered one of the most resilient softwoods in the commercial market and can handle really hard conditions. You&amp;rsquo;ll find it in older style houses or in large beams. Apparently, it was the go-to wood in the 19th century and was milled in all over Sydney. Now, apparently, Australia goes for treated pine for its lumber material as its quicker to grow and Douglas fir is less available. Our lumber comes from a timber mill that was closing down to make way for apartments and off cuts from a housing renovation.
Blackbutt is our wood of choice to frame our windows with Erny having the bright idea to make the window frames himself. It&amp;rsquo;s a ridiculously heavy native hardwood that has a gorgeous grain and colour. We picked up the planks at an auction house to save them from getting mulched as they have quite a few cracks and burls in them (or as some people like to say - character). It also smells different to the Douglas fir when it gets sawn - because it&amp;rsquo;s a hardwood. Since Blackbutt is so dense it causes the blade to heat up due to increased friction. This burns the wood and brings out a more burnt smell.
Wood Density Notes Douglas Fir 550kg/m3 Softwood Blackbutt 900kg/m3 Hardwood Also, we&amp;rsquo;re following part of the Unified Construction Method by Fred Schultz, by creating ply connectors for our roof rafters and have measured 23 of these out. Lys had to hunt high and low for a protractor that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been touched since Year 6 Maths.
Challenges We&amp;rsquo;ve had a string of pretty good weekends in June so can&amp;rsquo;t complain about the weather! ☀️🌧️ A thing we&amp;rsquo;re trying to tweak at the moment is finding fastest and most optimal way to set up our workspace since we&amp;rsquo;re working outside. Currently we&amp;rsquo;re putting out two fold out tables and using some spare agriculture pipe to manage particles.
What&amp;rsquo;s next? Erny&amp;rsquo;s flying out to the US for most of July and the forecast is looking pretty awful so it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that we&amp;rsquo;ll be getting much done this month. We&amp;rsquo;ll probably be writing up a bit more content as well catching everyone up on what we&amp;rsquo;ve been up to over the last 6 months too!
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny</description><category>build_update</category><category>tiny_house</category><category>blackbutt</category><category>douglas_fir</category></item><item><title>Hi I'm Miette</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/hi-im-miette/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 17:41:24 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/hi-im-miette/</guid><description>Hello World &amp;#x1f44b; My name is Lys and my partner Erny and I are building a tiny home made out of seconds, reclaimed and recycled materials. This is a small space on the interwebs to to document our progress and share our photos for anyone who would like to follow our journey! &amp;#x1f604;
Table Of Contents Why build a tiny house? Do you have any constraints? What does miette mean? So how&amp;rsquo;s it going? Why build a tiny house? Erny and I have always been interested in living more sustainably and living small. Then a pandemic hit and it seemed like a good idea to get started on making the dream a reality.
Do you have any constraints? We&amp;rsquo;re trying to do everything (bar trailer, electrical and plumbing) ourselves.
Other constraints include:
Buying second hand or borrowing tools (from tool libraries and benevolent friends) Going for second, reclaimed and recycled materials first (thank you Facebook marketplace &amp;#x2764;&amp;#xfe0f;) Having limited construction knowledge (however we have some amazing friends who do!) Working full time jobs with no plans on quitting them We&amp;rsquo;re also following the building principles of Fred&amp;rsquo;s Tiny Houses and his Unified Construction Method and Passive Haus Design principles.
What does miette mean? Miette is the french word for crumb or morsel. We chose it as we share a love of pastries, bread and all things that create tiny dust carbs but also because crumbs (like our budget) are small - like our tiny house! We also love the colour yellow - you&amp;rsquo;ll often see Erny running about in a yellow raincoat.
Other names that we bounced around included:
Le petit chou (the little cabbage) Wanda Inn The Blue Elephant Half Bark House Block House (after our favourite climbing gym) So how&amp;rsquo;s it going? It&amp;rsquo;s going very slooooooooooooooowly. We&amp;rsquo;ve bought the trailer and have now milled our wood but Covid, La Niña and general life have really halted our progress.
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny
Lys &amp;amp; Erny</description><category>tiny_house</category></item></channel></rss>