<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>build_update on The Miette</title>
    <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/build_update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in build_update on The Miette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 11:08:26 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/build_update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>April Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-apr-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-apr-build-update/</guid>
      <description>An April build update We got some walls up!
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done A timeline of sorts What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What a hectic last few days! Erny and I took some time off to focus on the tiny house full-time over the Easter break. For us, the past week has been a rollercoaster ride of highs and lows, with the weather constantly threatening to rain on our parade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/mar-2023-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/mar-2023-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A March build update A door, some floor progress and general reflections.
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Hello from The Miette HQ! The last half of February and March has been a busy and productive month for Erny and Lys, and thanks to an unseasonably dry month on the coast we have made some great progress on the tiny.
We kicked off the month by refurbishing our 40-year-old door.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/jan-2023-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/jan-2023-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A January build update We get glass in window frames.
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done In December last year Lys&amp;rsquo; parents gently highlighted that they want their garage back. So, with a deadline of September 30th and some wonderful sunshine we decided to nail these windows down. Honestly, we try write these blogs once a month but sometimes its difficult to encapsulate every trial and tribulation when you cannot even begin to remember them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November December Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/nov-dec-2022-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/nov-dec-2022-build-update/</guid>
      <description>An November December build update Window making continues with a side of weddings, berry farms, and other sundry end of year activities.
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done So while writing this blog post, Lys discovers there&amp;rsquo;s a frisbee emoji 🥏 also known as the flying disc emoji - how random! Tiny house wise though - our journey continues working on our windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oct Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/oct-2022-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/oct-2022-build-update/</guid>
      <description>An October build update We got solar! ☀️ ☀️ ☀️
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done One of our neighbours decided to demolish their house without removing their 10 year old solar system (it was not cost effective for them to re-install). Luckily for us they said that if we could take it down we could have it! Erny clambered onto the roof on a balmy Sunday day to bring the panels down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August September 2022 Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 13:54:47 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</guid>
      <description>An August September build update Hello Spring! Working almost every weekend, these last two months we&amp;rsquo;ve actually got a proper build update 😄.
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done We went through our stash of 90x45mm lengths and picked out roof rafters. These have been measured down to a 20 degree angle and some have been cut to size! We&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this in the garage when there has been a rain shower break and it has worked quite well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 2022 Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/july-2022-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 20:15:04 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/july-2022-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A July build update What have we done? Absolutely nothing. Lys honestly thinks it&amp;rsquo;s been the wettest July that we&amp;rsquo;ve lived through in sunny Australia.
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Erny jetted off to the US for a few weeks to play ultimate frisbee! Left to her own devices Lys did a few sundry things like source suppliers for our metal connectors. We&amp;rsquo;ve also added a few new features to the site - now you can add comments and now subscribe if you feel so inclined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2022 Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/june-2022-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 23:15:04 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/june-2022-build-update/</guid>
      <description>A June build update Decided that we should do monthly build updates as we march towards the end of the year. We&amp;rsquo;re hoping to reach lock up by then (walls, floor and roof complete) and 31st December is our D-day.
Table Of ContentsWhat we&amp;rsquo;ve done Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Erny bought a second hand table saw for $400 a few months back and it&amp;rsquo;s been an absolute workhorse.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
