<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Oiling on The Miette</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/oiling/</link><description>Recent content in Oiling on The Miette</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 15:15:56 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/oiling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2025 May to Aug Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2025-may-to-aug-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 15:15:56 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2025-may-to-aug-build-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>News flash: our house is now an appliance!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just kidding — but it &lt;em>has&lt;/em> started to feel that way with the electrics coming online this month and once again, we know it&amp;rsquo;s August, and last build update was in May but we&amp;rsquo;ve been really trying to make serious progress this build. We also know that we had a planned move in date for May&amp;hellip;and that did not happen obviously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But why is the tiny house an appliance? Read on to find out 😊&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>July Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jul-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jul-build-update/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-july-build-update">A July build update&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Windows are in!&lt;/p>
&lt;div>
 &lt;h6>Table Of Contents&lt;/h6>
 &lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#what-weve-done">What we&amp;rsquo;ve done&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#working-on-the-water-pooling-solution">Working on the water pooling solution&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#whats-next">What’s next?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h4 id="what-weve-done">What we&amp;rsquo;ve done&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>July has been window month. We are pretty proud to say that we&amp;rsquo;ve now got our hand made windows installed 🙂 - here is how it went!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We began with the bathroom window, which we thought would be a breeze. However, not even one window down we faced our first hiccup - it turns out the width of the window frame was not wide enough to run flush with the internal lining of the tiny house (on the inside) and flush with the exterior cladding on the outside. We were 8 mm short! Talk about a stressful first window weekend. After some deliberation we decided that we would cut an angle into our internal lining and make it a feature. This means that the exterior cladding will be flush giving a more waterproof seal, and we will have to get creative when we tackle the interior. Bar this - the bathroom window went in without a hitch!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>