<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Youtube on The Miette</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/youtube/</link><description>Recent content in Youtube on The Miette</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:20:37 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/youtube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>June July Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-june-july-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:20:37 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-june-july-build-update/</guid><description>Hello! It’s another double month build update, not by design but by necessity as we have been working hard to make this tiny house more of a reality. June saw us work on our kitchen cabinets while we wait for the professionals and buying an HRV system, and July saw us getting all our insulation done! We watched many hours of Tour de France and as Lys writes this the Olympics is on in the background, so we are feeling very inspired watching others achieve their goals.</description></item><item><title>April and May Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-apr-may-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 13:04:21 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-apr-may-build-update/</guid><description>My goodness hasn’t it been a time — feels like we haven’t written a post in a long time. Looking back, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe how quickly time has flown by. April and May seem like distant memories, and now, here we are, well into&amp;hellip;July. But we haven’t been sleeping and not working — let me take you through the latest updates and progress we&amp;rsquo;ve made during these transformative months.</description></item><item><title>Jan Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-jan-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-jan-build-update/</guid><description>Our first update for 2024! 2024 has well and truly started with what feels like a huge January. Among the noteworthy developments was new eye protection! But jokes aside, we got some new eye-glasses from Bunnings and these are crystal clear with exceptional comfort, with Erny forgetting that they’re even on his face or on his head. They have swiftly become an indispensable asset — and it’s the little things, you know?</description></item><item><title>June Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jun-build-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-jun-build-update/</guid><description>A June build update A lot of shopping and finally finishing sanding the cladding!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done The tail end of May and the month of June have been quite eventful, filled with a lot of shopping and unexpected visitors from far away states. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in!
Our fanciest acquisition was a package of flathead brass screws that arrived in the mail.</description></item><item><title>May Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-may-build-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-may-build-update/</guid><description>An May build update Wrapping the tiny house like a present 🎁🎁🎁
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Hello, hello! As May rolls on, the days are getting shorter, and our productivity has slowed down. Not to make this blog become a Let's complain about the weather blog, but with the weather changing, we&amp;rsquo;ve had to battle with the elements to get any work done. Sunny weekdays are always followed by rainy weekends, leaving us only a few good hours to work on our project.</description></item><item><title>April Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-apr-build-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2023-apr-build-update/</guid><description>An April build update We got some walls up!
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done A timeline of sorts What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done What a hectic last few days! Erny and I took some time off to focus on the tiny house full-time over the Easter break. For us, the past week has been a rollercoaster ride of highs and lows, with the weather constantly threatening to rain on our parade.</description></item><item><title>How To Build a Window</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/how-to-build-a-window/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/how-to-build-a-window/</guid><description>Just a short update - Lys put together a little montage of our window building journey (over 8 months in the making) and we have started tackling the doors! Will update our door journey in the next post but for now enjoy the video!
Catch ya later, Lys &amp;amp; Erny</description></item><item><title>November December Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/nov-dec-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/nov-dec-2022-build-update/</guid><description>An November December build update Window making continues with a side of weddings, berry farms, and other sundry end of year activities.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done So while writing this blog post, Lys discovers there&amp;rsquo;s a frisbee emoji 🥏 also known as the flying disc emoji - how random! Tiny house wise though - our journey continues working on our windows.</description></item><item><title>Oct Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/oct-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 11:08:26 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/oct-2022-build-update/</guid><description>An October build update We got solar! ☀️ ☀️ ☀️
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done One of our neighbours decided to demolish their house without removing their 10 year old solar system (it was not cost effective for them to re-install). Luckily for us they said that if we could take it down we could have it! Erny clambered onto the roof on a balmy Sunday day to bring the panels down.</description></item><item><title>August September 2022 Build Update</title><link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 13:54:47 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/aug-sep-2022-build-update/</guid><description>An August September build update Hello Spring! Working almost every weekend, these last two months we&amp;rsquo;ve actually got a proper build update &amp;#x1f604;.
Table Of Contents What we&amp;rsquo;ve done Highlights Challenges What&amp;rsquo;s next? What we&amp;rsquo;ve done We went through our stash of 90x45mm lengths and picked out roof rafters. These have been measured down to a 20 degree angle and some have been cut to size! We&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this in the garage when there has been a rain shower break and it has worked quite well.</description></item></channel></rss>