<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>plywood on The Miette</title>
    <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/plywood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in plywood on The Miette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:33:10 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/plywood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>October, November and December Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-oct-nov-dec-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:33:10 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-oct-nov-dec-build-update/</guid>
      <description>Happy 2025! We hope you&amp;rsquo;ve had a restful festive season 🎄🎉. Time doesn’t just fly — it seems to sprint when you’re building a tiny house. Going to pack updates for October, November, and December in this build update, there’s been a lot more construction than reflection and writing. But, as we reminisce on the past three months, it’s clear how much we’ve accomplished, as we continue to chip away at our goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June and July Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-june-july-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:20:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-june-july-build-update/</guid>
      <description>Hello! It’s another double month build update, not by design but by necessity as we have been working hard to make this tiny house more of a reality. June saw us work on our kitchen cabinets while we wait for the professionals and buying an HRV system, and July saw us getting all our insulation done! We watched many hours of Tour de France and as Lys writes this the Olympics is on in the background, so we are feeling very inspired watching others achieve their goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February and March Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-feb-mar-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 14:51:27 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-feb-mar-build-update/</guid>
      <description>Well hello there, long time no write. Not really sure where all the time went, but let’s start in February and make our way through the months, shall we?
Table Of ContentsFebruary - Breaks and Supply Chain Delays March Easter Build-Athlon What&amp;rsquo;s next? February - Breaks and Supply Chain Delays To begin, in February, our tiny house project took a bit of a breather, allowing us to indulge in some personal pursuits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
