<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kitchen on The Miette</title>
    <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/kitchen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kitchen on The Miette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 15:15:56 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lysng.github.io/themiette/tags/kitchen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025 May to Aug Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2025-may-to-aug-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 15:15:56 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2025-may-to-aug-build-update/</guid>
      <description>News flash: our house is now an appliance!
Just kidding — but it has started to feel that way with the electrics coming online this month and once again, we know it&amp;rsquo;s August, and last build update was in May but we&amp;rsquo;ve been really trying to make serious progress this build. We also know that we had a planned move in date for May&amp;hellip;and that did not happen obviously.
But why is the tiny house an appliance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 January to May Build Update: Progress, Travel, and Tiny Wins</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2025-january-to-may-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 18:56:57 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2025-january-to-may-build-update/</guid>
      <description>Oh, heyyyy long time no see&amp;hellip;it’s been a little while since we’ve updated you all — five months, to be exact! Between travelling, working, and chipping away at the house, the blog has definitely fallen to the wayside, but we’re back with plenty to share. Let’s dive into what’s been keeping us busy over the past few months. Spoiler alert: we’ve made progress, but as usual our timeline has been blown out of the window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June and July Build Update</title>
      <link>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-june-july-build-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:20:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lysng.github.io/themiette/posts/2024-june-july-build-update/</guid>
      <description>Hello! It’s another double month build update, not by design but by necessity as we have been working hard to make this tiny house more of a reality. June saw us work on our kitchen cabinets while we wait for the professionals and buying an HRV system, and July saw us getting all our insulation done! We watched many hours of Tour de France and as Lys writes this the Olympics is on in the background, so we are feeling very inspired watching others achieve their goals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
